[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
SPEAKER 1: All right.
好的。
So this is CS50, and this is week four.
所以这是 CS50，这是第四周。
And this is actually one of the weeks that
这实际上是其中一周，
really makes CS50, CS50, insofar as we'll
让 CS50 成为 CS50 的关键一周，因为我们将会
take an even lower level look at how computers work,
以更低级的视角来观察计算机的工作原理，
and in turn, what it is you're doing when you write code
反过来，也让你了解你在编写代码时所做的事情
toward an end of really giving you a complete mental model of what's
最终是为了让你对计算机内部发生的一切有一个完整的模型，这样当你想
going on inside, so that when you run to solve some problem, when you want
解决问题的时候，当你想要
to fix, solve some problem, when you want to write some code,
修复或解决问题，当你想要编写一些代码的时候，
you actually know what those building blocks inside of the computer
你实际上就会知道计算机内部的那些构建块
itself actually are.
本身是什么。
We'll, ultimately, too, take off some of the training wheels
最终，我们也会去掉一些辅助工具，
that we've had on for the past few weeks, particularly in C,
比如过去几周一直在使用的工具，特别是 C 语言中的工具，
and we'll also introduce more familiar media types.
我们还将介绍一些更常见的媒体类型。
So files, like images are sort of everywhere.
所以，像图片这样的文件无处不在。
And we'll introduce you to exactly what's
我们将会向你介绍，当你看到照片、GIF
going on when you just look at a photograph, or a GIF,
或者 PNG 以及屏幕上的任何其他图像，比如这个图像的时候，到底发生了什么。
or a PNG, or any kind of image on your screen like this one here.
这将会变得清晰起来，不像好莱坞的电视剧和电影，
And it will become clear that, unlike Hollywood TV shows and movies,
如果你尝试将这样的图片进行放大，再放大，再放大，在电影中，通常
if you try to enhance a picture like this
是为了找出坏人是谁，最后，
to look closer, and closer, and closer, in the movies typically
你会发现信息不足，因为这些文件只有有限数量的比特
trying to figure out who the bad guy is, for instance, eventually,
或者字节。
you run out of information because there's only a finite number of bits
所以，如果你看到计算机上，只需要
or bytes that compose these files.
点击一个按钮，然后“嘭”的一声，图片就被放大了，然后嫌疑人突然就清晰了，
So any time you've seen computers that you just
那更像是好莱坞的电影，而不是计算机科学。
hit a button, and boom, it's enhanced, and all of a sudden the suspect
但话虽如此，在学期后期，我们会
is clear, that's a lot more Hollywood than it is computer science.
谈论人工智能。
But with that said, later in the term, we
即使在那里可能没有那些信息，
will talk about artificial intelligence.
通过统计推理、建模和预测，
And even though there might not be that information there,
计算机越来越能够实际地创造
through statistical reasoning, and modeling, and predictions,
信息，即使这些信息可能不存在，仅仅是基于
can computers increasingly actually create
最有可能出现的场景。
information, where perhaps there was none, just based
再过不久，我们会详细介绍这些内容。
on what's most likely to be there?
但你会看到，屏幕上的所有这些点，所有的像素，
So more on that before long, too.
可以看作是一个上下左右的网格，
But you'll see that all of these dots on the screen, all of these pixels,
这些网格组成了图像。
so to speak, are just a grid up, down, left, right that
我们很幸运地邀请到了三位志愿者上台，
compose these pictures.
他们在讲座开始之前，利用便签纸创作了自己的像素艺术作品，
And we're fortunate to have three volunteers on stage who
可以说，是利用这台画架创作的。
kindly, just before the lecture began, created their own pixel artwork,
如果你们愿意，可以把这台画架转过来，
so to speak, on this here easel.
让我们看看你们都做了些什么。
If you guys would like to spin this around,
另外，如果你们愿意，可以向我们介绍一下自己，
let's see what it is you've been working on.
作为我们今天的三位艺术家。
And if you'd like to introduce yourselves as our three artists
好的。
today, first.
我是 Talia。
SPEAKER 2: Yes, I'm Talia.
我是一名大三学生，主修经济学，辅修计算机科学。
I'm a junior at the college studying economics with a possible computer
你好。
science secondary.
我叫 Bulut。
SPEAKER 3: Hi.
我来自波士顿大学。
My name is Bulut.
欢迎。
I'm from BU.
我是 Assalo Caesar，是一位自学成才的计算机科学学生。
SPEAKER 1: Welcome.
我从 16 岁开始就从事软件工程师的工作。
SPEAKER 4: I'm a Assalo Caesar, self-taught computer science student.
不错。
I've been working as a software engineer since age 16.
欢迎你们。
SPEAKER 1: Nice.
另外，请你们描述一下你们用像素制作了什么。
Well, welcome to you all.
我们做了一个烟花。
And if you would like to give us a description of what it
好的，不错。
is that you built out of pixels here.
因为我们给他们的都是便签纸，每个便签纸都代表着一个像素或者点。
SPEAKER 2: So we built a firework.
通常来说，可能只有黑色或白色，
SPEAKER 1: OK, nice.
但是我们这里的便签纸是粉色或蓝色。
And it's very blocky because what we've given
所以，每一个便签纸都代表着屏幕上的一个点。
them is post-it notes, each of which represents one of these pixels or dots.
我记得你们还做了一个作品，
Now, typically, it might be black or white,
可能传达了更多信息，如果你们愿意，可以展示一下第二版本。
but the post-it notes we have here are pink or blue.
我们又有了更多的像素艺术作品。
So each of these represents a dot on the screen.
让我们为我们的志愿者鼓掌，他们仅凭像素就完成了这些作品。
And I gather you did one other that actually
谢谢。
conveys maybe a bit more information, if you want to reveal version two.
我们一如既往地准备了美味的超级马里奥兄弟奥利奥饼干，
And thus we have yet more pixel art.
给在场的每一位。
So maybe round of applause for what our volunteers were able to do using
非常感谢你们上来。
pixels alone.
谢谢。
Thank you.
但关键是，
We have, as always, limited supply of delicious Super Mario Brothers
当屏幕上只有点的时候，你能做的事情就有限。
Oreos for each of you.
当然，我们刚才看到的那个
Thank you so much for coming up.
减压球的图片，质量更高。
But thank you.
保真度更高，或者更准确地说，分辨率更高。
But the point here, really, is that there's
而分辨率指的是屏幕上的点或像素数量。
only so much you can do when you just have dots on the screen.
它们越小，屏幕上塞得越多，图像就越清晰。
Now, of course, the image that we saw a moment ago of these
但最终，即使像这种像素艺术作品
here stress balls is much higher quality.
也代表着你手机、笔记本电脑、台式机、电视上正在发生的事情，
It's much higher fidelity, or more specifically, much higher resolution.
因为它们都是像素网格。
And resolution just refers to how many dots or pixels are on the screen.
现在，在编写实际操作这些图像的代码之前，我们需要了解，
And the smaller they are, and the more you
我们需要掌握一些用于导航文件的新语法。
cram in on the screen, the clearer, and clearer the images are.
不仅是文本，还有存储在计算机上的文件，
But at the end of the day, even this here pixel art
存储在服务器上的文件。
represents what's going on your phone, your laptop, your desktop, your TV
但是，让我们考虑一下如何存储像这样的信息，
nowadays, because all it is this grid of pixels.
但我们会简化它。
Now, before we can actually write code that actually manipulates
这里有一个 0 和 1 的网格，显然。
these kinds of images, we need to understand,
但我认为，每一个 0 或 1 都可以代表
and we need to have some new syntax for navigating files.
一个像素，一个点。
So not just text, but files stored somewhere on the computer,
如果这个点是 0，它就代表黑色。
somewhere on the server.
But let's consider how we might store even information like this.
But we'll make it simpler.
Here is a grid of zeros and ones, clearly.
But I would argue that each of these might as well represent
a pixel, an individual dot.
And if that dot is a zero, it's representing the color black.
If that dot is a one, it's representing the color white.
如果那个点是 1，它就代表白色。
Given that, can anyone see what this grid is a picture of,
这样的话，有人能看出这个网格是什么图案吗？
even though it's using zeros and ones and not post-it notes, like this here?
即使它使用的是 0 和 1，而不是便签，就像这里一样？
Yeah, in the back?
嗯，在后面吗？
It's a smiley face.
这是一个笑脸。
How do you see that?
你怎么看出来的？
Well, in a moment it's going to be super obvious.
好吧，一会儿就会非常明显。
But if I actually get rid of the ones, leaving just the zeros,
但如果我真的去掉 1，只留下 0，
there you have the zeros that were there just a moment ago.
这些 0 就出现了，它们刚刚才在那里。
So what this translates to, typically on a screen,
所以，通常在屏幕上，这会被转化成
is not a pattern of zeros and ones literally on the screen,
不是屏幕上的 0 和 1 的模式，
but a pattern of dots.
而是一系列点的模式。
So again, white might be one, and black might be--
所以，再次强调，白色可能是 1，而黑色可能是——
one might be white.
1 可能代表白色。
Zero might be black.
0 可能代表黑色。
But we picture it, of course, on our screens as this actual grid.
但当然，我们在屏幕上看到的是这个网格。
But that's really all we need.
但实际上，这就是我们所需要的。
Inside of a file to store something like an image,
在存储图像之类的文件里，
we just need a pattern of zeros and ones.
我们只需要一系列的 0 和 1。
But of course, having more colors would be more interesting.
但当然，拥有更多颜色会更有趣。
And if you actually have a larger grid, you can do even more with pixel art.
如果你有一个更大的网格，你就可以用像素画做更多的事情。
And in fact for fun, at the beginning of the semester,
事实上，为了好玩，在学期开始的时候，
we have a staff training with all of the teaching fellows, course assistants,
我们会对所有助教、课程助理进行培训，
teaching assistants, and we gave them all this Google spreadsheet.
助教，然后我们给他们所有人一个 Google 表格。
And we sort of resized all of the rows and columns
我们调整了所有行和列的大小
to just be squares instead of the default rectangles.
使它们变成正方形而不是默认的矩形。
And then we encouraged them to create something out of this.
然后我们鼓励他们用这个表格创作一些东西。
And in fact, just a few weeks ago, here are some of this year's creations,
事实上，就在几周前，这里有一些今年的作品，
creating, essentially, images using Google Spreadsheets
使用 Google 表格创建图像，
by treating each of the cells as just a dot on the screen.
将每个单元格视为屏幕上的一个点。
So here, we have a team who in a few minutes
所以，这里有一个团队，在几分钟内
made a Super Mario World, a bigger canvas, of course,
做了一个超级马里奥世界，当然，画布比这里更大。
than this here easel.
比这里画架更大。
Here we have a pixel based version of Scratch.
这里有一个基于像素的 Scratch 版本。
Here, we had an homage to the Harvard-Yale football competition.
这里，我们向哈佛-耶鲁橄榄球比赛致敬。
And then here, we had a character of some sort.
然后这里，我们有一个角色。
So this is what the team here did.
所以这是这个团队做的事情。
And actually, if you'd like to play along at home
实际上，如果你想在家玩玩
at the risk of distracting you the entirety of lecture,
冒着让你整节课都分心的风险，
if you go to this URL here, it'll actually give you
如果你访问这个 URL，它会给你
a copy of that same blank spreadsheet.
一个相同的空白表格的副本。
But let's talk about representing, not just zeros and ones,
但让我们谈谈如何表示，不仅仅是 0 和 1，
and black and white, but actual colors.
还有黑白色，而是真实的颜色。
And so recall from week zero when we talked
所以，回想一下我们第一周讲的
about how to represent information, colors among,
如何表示信息，颜色在其中，
them we introduced RGB, which stands for red, green, blue.
我们介绍了 RGB，代表红、绿、蓝。
And it's just this kind of convention of using some amount of red,
它就是一种约定，使用一定量的红色，
some amount of green, and some amount of blue mixed together to give you
一定量的绿色，和一定量的蓝色混合在一起，给你
the actual color that you want.
你想要的颜色。
Well, it turns out in the world of computers,
好吧，在计算机的世界里，
there's a standard way for describing those amounts of red, green, and blue.
有一种标准的方式来描述这些红、绿、蓝的量。
At the end of the day, it's of course just bits.
归根结底，它只是比特。
And equivalently, it's just numbers, like 72, 73,
等效地，它只是数字，比如 72、73，
33 was the arbitrary example we used in week zero for the color yellow.
33 是我们第一周用来表示黄色的任意例子。
But there actually tends to be a different notation by convention
但实际上，根据惯例，有一种不同的表示颜色的符号
for representing colors that we'll actually see today, too,
我们会今天看到，
as we explore the world of memory.
当我们探索记忆的世界。
So here's a screenshot of Photoshop.
这是一张 Photoshop 的截图。
If you've never used it before, this is like the color picker
如果你以前从未使用过它，它就像一个颜色选择器
that you can pull up, just to pick any number of millions of colors
你可以调出来，选择数百万种颜色中的任何一种
by clicking and dragging, or typing in numbers.
通过点击拖动，或输入数字。
But notice down here.
但请注意这里。
We've picked at the moment the color black by moving
我们现在选择黑色，通过移动
the slider all the way down here to the bottom left hand corner.
滑块到底部左角。
And what this user interface is telling us
这个用户界面告诉我们
is that there's zero red, zero green, zero blue.
没有红色，没有绿色，没有蓝色。
And a conventional way of writing this on a screen
在屏幕上写这个的常规方法是
would be, literally, a hash symbol, and then three pairs of digits.
一个井号，然后是三个数字对。
zero, zero for red, zero, zero for green, zero, zero for blue.
00 代表红色，00 代表绿色，00 代表蓝色。
If by contrast, you were to pick the color, say, white in Photoshop,
相反，如果你在 Photoshop 中选择白色，
it gets a little weird.
事情变得有点奇怪。
Now it's a lot of red, a lot of green, a lot of blue, as you might expect,
现在有很多红色，很多绿色，很多蓝色，正如你所料，
cranking all of those values up.
将所有这些值都调到最大。
But the way you write it conventionally is not using decimal,
但你写它的常规方式不是使用十进制，
but using letters of the alphabet, it would seem here.
而是使用字母，看起来是。
So FF for red, FF, for Green, FF for blue.
所以 FF 代表红色，FF 代表绿色，FF 代表蓝色。
More on that in a moment.
稍后详细说明。
When it comes to representing red, here's a lot of red, 255.
当涉及到表示红色时，这里有很多红色，255。
Zero green, zero blue.
零绿色，零蓝色。
And so the pattern is now FF0000.
所以模式现在是 FF0000。
Before I reveal what green is, what probably should it be?
在揭示绿色是什么之前，它可能应该是？
What pattern?
什么模式？
Yeah.
是的。
Close.
接近。
Not 0000FF, but 00FF00 because it seems to be following this pattern, indeed,
不是 0000FF，而是 00FF00，因为它似乎遵循这种模式，确实，
from left to right of red, green, blue.
从左到右是红、绿、蓝。
So zero red, 255 green, zero blue, and thus 00FF00.
所以是零红色，255 绿色，零蓝色，因此是 00FF00。
And then lastly, if we do solid blue, it's zero red, zero green,
最后，如果我们使用纯蓝色，它是零红色，零绿色，
a lot of blue, and thus 0000FF.
很多蓝色，因此是 0000FF。
So somehow or other, FF is apparently representing the number 255.
所以不知何故，FF 显然代表数字 255。
And we'll see why in just a moment.
我们很快就会明白原因。
But recall that in the world of computers,
但请记住，在计算机的世界里，
they just speak zeros and ones.
它们只说 0 和 1。
And we've seen that already in black and white form.
我们已经在黑白形式中看到了这一点。
We of course, in the real world, tend to use decimal instead of binary.
当然，在现实世界中，我们倾向于使用十进制而不是二进制。
So we have 10 digits at our disposal, zero through nine.
所以我们有十个数字可以使用，从零到九。
But it turns out that in the world of graphics and colors,
但事实证明，在图形和颜色的世界里，
turns out in the world of computer memory,
事实证明，在计算机内存的世界里，
it tends to be convenient not to use binary, per se, not to use decimal,
通常情况下，不使用二进制，也不使用十进制，
per se, but to use something called hexadecimal,
而是使用一种叫做十六进制的东西，
where as soon as you need more than 10 digits total,
只要你需要的数字超过10位，
you start stealing from the English alphabet.
你就会开始从英文字母表中窃取。
So the next few numbers, or digits rather,
所以接下来的几个数字，或者更确切地说，是数字，
are A, B, C, D, E, F. And there's other systems that
是 A、B、C、D、E、F。还有其他系统使用更多字母，但可能是
use even more letters of the alphabet, but this is probably
我们最后一次详细讨论的。
the last we'll discuss in any detail.
所以，在这种情况下，我们共有 10 加 1，2，3，4，5，
So in this case, we have a total of 10 plus one, two, three, four, five,
6，一共 16 个，也就是
six, so 16 total, a.k.a.
十六进制，或者我们称之为 16 进制。
hexadecimal, or what we might call base 16.
大小写实际上并不重要。
And the capitalization actually doesn't matter.
通常使用大写或小写，
It's conventional to use uppercase or lowercase,
只要你大体上保持一致。
so long as you're generally consistent.
所以，hexa 代表 16，decimal 代表十进制。
So hexa, implying 16, decimal.
因此，十六进制表示法，也称为 16 进制，
So hexadecimal notation here, or otherwise known as base 16,
由于数学原因，可以追溯到我们第零周的讨论。
for mathematical reasons that go back to our discussion in week zero.
所以这里有一些来自第零周的相同推理。
So here's some of that same reasoning from week zero.
我们如何用十六进制的两位数来表示你我所知的十进制数？
How might we go about representing using two
好吧，如果我们认为这是 16 的零次方，16
digits in hexadecimal, different numbers that you and I know as decimal?
到一次方，如果我们进行计算，当然，
Well, if we consider this as being the 16 to the zeros place, 16
这给了我们个位和十六位。
to the ones place, and if we do out that math, of course,
所以我们只改变了基数，而不是第零周的故事。
that gives us the ones place and the sixteens place.
所以，如果我们要开始用十六进制表示实际的值，
So we've only changed the base, not the story from week zero.
这里有两个零。
So if we were to start representing actual values in hexadecimal,
所以，是 1 乘以 0 加 16 乘以 0，当然，这给了我们
here are two zeros.
你我所知的数字零。
So that's 1 times 0 plus 16 times 0, which, of course, gives us
所以，在十六进制、二进制和十进制中，
the number you and I know is zero.
表示你我所知的数字零的方法是相同的。
So in hexadecimal, and in binary, and in decimal, it's
但这里现在是十六进制的数字一。
the same way to represent the number you and I know as zero.
这里是数字二。
But here now is the number one in hexadecimal.
这里是数字三、四、五、六、七、八、九。
Here's the number two.
所以，到目前为止，它与我们的十进制世界是相同的。
Here's the number three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
但我如何将你我所说的十进制的10计算出来，
So it's identical up until this point to our world of decimal.
根据我们目前所看到的？
But how do I count up to what you and I would call 10 in decimal,
是的。
according to what we're seeing here thus far?
所以现在它上升到 A，因为 A 似乎
Yeah.
代表你我所知的 10。
So now it goes up to A, because A would, apparently,
B 代表 11。
represent what you and I know as 10.
C 代表 12、13、14、15。
B represents 11.
不过，我如何将 16 计算出来？
C represents 12, 13, 14, 15.
是的。
How, though, do I count up to 16?
确实。
Yeah.
所以不是 10，而是 1，0，因为左边第二列的 1
Exactly.
实际上代表的是十六位。
So not 10, quote unquote, but one, zero because the one
所以 16 乘以 1 等于 16，加上 1 乘以 0 等于 0，所以总共是 16。
in the second column here to the left actually represents the sixteens place.
所以，现在是你可以我所认为的 17 的数字，
So it's 16 times 1 gives you 16, plus 1 times 0 gives you 0, so 16 in total.
18、19、20、21，等等。
So this now is the way the number you and I would think of as 17,
如果我们一直数下去，尽可能地数下去，那么十六进制中最大的数字是什么？
18, 19, 20, 21, dot, dot, dot.
显然，最小的数字是 0，我说过最大的数字是 F。
And if we go all the way up, as high up as we
所以，当你到达 FF 时，数学就会变得有点烦人。
can count, well, what's the largest digit, apparently, in hexadecimal?
但现在是 16 乘以 15 加 1 乘以 15。
The smallest is clearly zero, and the biggest I said was F.
实际上，这给了我们你我所知的数字 255。
So once you get to FF, the math gets a little annoying.
所以，我们在 Photoshop 中看到了它。
But this is now 16 times 15 plus 1 times 15.
我们现在在十六进制中看到了它。
And what that gives us, actually, is the number you and I know as 255.
这不是你会经常做的数学，
So we saw it in Photoshop.
但实际上，它与第零周的系统完全相同，
We've seen it now in hexadecimal.
只是基数不同。
This is not math that you would ever do frequently,
但为什么有这么多额外的复杂性？
but indeed, it's the exact same system as week zero,
为什么我们要跳过这些障碍，引入另一个障碍，
just with a different base.
只是为了给我们提供像这样的 FF 模式？
But why all of this additional complexity?
事实证明，十六进制只是很方便。
Why are we jumping through these hoops introducing yet another one
为什么呢？
to give us just some pattern like this of FF?
好吧，如果你在你的字母表中有 16 个数字，
Well, it turns out that hexadecimal is just convenient.
从 0 到 F，你需要多少位，多少个 0 和 1 来
Why?
表示 16 个不同的值？
Well, if you have 16 digits in your alphabet,
是 4 位，对吧？
zero through F, how many bits, how many zeros and ones
因为如果你有 4 位，那就是第一个的两种可能性乘以
do you need to represent 16 different values?
2，乘以 2，乘以 2。
It's four, right?
所以是 16 种可能性。
Because if you've got four bits, that's two possibilities for the first times
2 的四次方。
2, times 2, times 2.
所以如果你有 4 位，由一个数字表示，
So that's 16 possibilities.
对计算机科学家和程序员来说，这在实践中非常方便。
2 to the fourth power.
所以 F 可能会代表 1111。
And if you've got four bits represented by a single digit,
但这并不是一个完整的字节，一个字节是 8 位。
it's just convenient in practice for computer scientists and programmers.
在计算中，没有人以 4 为单位计数。
So F might indeed represent 1111.
它总是以 8、16、32、64 等为单位。
But that's not a full byte, which is eight bits.
所以，事实证明，由于十六进制适合
And no one counts in units of four in computing.
一次表示 4 位，如果你只使用其中两个，
It's always in units of, like, eight, or 16, or 32, or 64, or the like.
你可以一次表示 8 位。
So it turns out, though, because hexadecimal lends itself
而 8 位是一个字节，这是一个常见的度量单位。
to representing four bits at a time, well, if you just use two of them,
这就是为什么即使是 Photoshop 也使用这种惯例，颜色程序也是如此，
you can represent eight bits at a time.
web 开发一般来说，使用两个十六进制数字来表示单个字节。
And eight bits is a byte, which is a common unit of measure.
因为左边的那个表示第一个比特，前四个比特。
And this is why even Photoshop uses this convention, as do color programs,
右边的那个代表后四个比特。
as does web development, more generally, of using two hexadecimal digits just
所以，这不是什么大问题。
to represent single bytes.
只是很方便，即使这可能让人感觉一下子太多了。
Because the one on the left represents the first bits, the first four bits.
那么，关于十六进制还有什么问题吗？
The one on the right represents the second four bits.
是的，中间那位。
So it's not a big deal, per se.
没有。
It's just convenient, even though this might feel like a lot all at once.
OK, no.
好的，没有。
Questions on hexadecimal.
关于十六进制的问题。
All right.
好的。
So with this system in mind, let's go about considering where else we might
所以带着这个系统，我们来思考一下，在其他什么地方我们可能会
see this in the computing world.
在计算世界中看到它。
And I would propose that we consider, as we've done in the past,
我建议我们考虑一下，就像我们过去做的那样，
that our computer is really just this grid of memory, for instance,
我们的计算机实际上只是一个内存网格，例如，
where each of these squares represents a single byte.
其中每个方格代表一个字节。
And I proposed a couple of times already that, when
我已经提出过几次，当
we talk about a computer's memory, we can
我们谈论计算机内存时，我们可以
think of them as each of these squares as having an individual location.
把它们想象成每个方格都有一个单独的位置。
Like, I spitballed back in the day that maybe this is the first byte,
比如，我以前随意地说，也许这是第一个字节，
the second byte, the third byte.
第二个字节，第三个字节。
Maybe this is the billionth byte, so we can number
也许这是十亿分之一字节，所以我们可以对
of the bytes inside of a computer.
计算机内部的字节进行编号。
Well, it turns out, as we'll see today in code,
事实证明，正如我们今天在代码中所见，
computers typically use numbers, indeed, to represent
计算机通常使用数字，实际上，来表示
all of the bytes in their memory, and they typically
它们内存中的所有字节，并且它们通常
use hexadecimal notation for such by convention.
按照惯例使用十六进制表示法。
So what do I mean by that?
那我的意思是？
Technically, if we were to start numbering these
从技术上讲，如果我们要开始给这些
and count at zero, as most programmers would,
进行编号，并从零开始计数，正如大多数程序员会做的那样，
this is byte zero, one, two, three, dot, dot, dot.
这是字节零，一，二，三，等等。
This is byte 15.
这是字节15。
But if I wanted to keep going, it would be then 16, 17, 18,
但是如果我想继续，那将是16，17，18，
but that's not the true in hexadecimal.
但这在十六进制中并不正确。
So instead in hexadecimal, once you hit the nine,
因此在十六进制中，一旦你达到九，
you'd actually use A through F, just as I've proposed.
你实际上会使用 A 到 F，正如我所提议的那样。
Meanwhile, if you kept going thereafter, you would have one zero.
同时，如果你继续往下，你会得到一个零。
But as you noted, this is not 10.
但正如你所注意到的，这不是10。
This is 16 here, 17, 18, 19.
这是16，17，18，19。
And so here's where things get a little weird.
所以这里事情就有点奇怪了。
I'm saying 16.
我说的是16。
I'm saying 17, and you're obviously seeing what any reasonable person would
我说的是17，你显然看到了任何理性的人都会
read as 10 and 11.
读成10和11。
So there's this dichotomy, and so we need some convention
所以存在这种二分法，因此我们需要一些约定
for making clear to the reader that these are hexadecimal numbers, not
让读者清楚地知道这些是十六进制数，而不是
decimal.
十进制。
Otherwise, it's completely ambiguous.
否则，它完全模棱两可。
And the convention there, which you might have seen in the real world,
那里的约定，你可能在现实世界中见过，
even though it's a bit weird, is just to prefix hexadecimal numbers with zero X.
尽管有点奇怪，但仅仅是在十六进制数前加一个零 X。
It's not doing anything mathematically.
它在数学上没有任何作用。
It's not multiplication or anything like that.
它不是乘法，也不是任何类似的东西。
Just zero X means, here comes a hexadecimal number hereafter, just
仅仅是零 X 意味着，这里将有一个十六进制数，仅此而已
to distinguish it from decimal.
用来区分它和十进制。
And you can see that, even though we don't have enough room for 255 bytes,
你可以看到，尽管我们没有足够的空间容纳 255 个字节，
you start to see patterns that we haven't even
你开始看到一些我们甚至还没有
talked about yet because we're just using those two columns as the ones
讨论过，因为我们只是使用这两列作为个位
place, the 16th place, and so forth.
位，第十六位，等等。
Capital or uppercase is fine.
大写或小写都可以。
All right.
好的。
So with that said, let's actually do things more technically interesting,
所以说，让我们做一些更技术上有趣的事情，
like looking back at some code that we've already seen
比如回顾一下我们已经看过的代码
and seeing what we can actually glean from this newfound representation
并看看我们实际上能从这种新发现的表示中得到什么
of memory location.
内存位置。
So I'm going to go over to VS Code here, where I've opened my terminal window,
所以我要到这里的 VS Code 中，我在那里打开了我的终端窗口，
but no code file yet.
但还没有代码文件。
And I'm going to go ahead and create a file called addresses.c
我要创建一个名为 addresses.c 的文件
because I want to start playing around now with the addresses of information
因为我想现在开始玩弄一下信息的地址
in my computer.
在我的计算机中。
And to do this, let me do something super simple first.
为了做到这一点，让我先做一些非常简单的事情。
Let me include standard io.h.
让我包含标准 io.h。
Let me do an int main void, no command line arguments.
让我做一个 int main void，没有命令行参数。
And then in here, let me do exactly the line of code we just saw.
然后在这里，让我做我们刚看到的这一行代码。
Declare an int called n, set it equal to a default value of 50.
声明一个名为 n 的 int，将其设置为默认值为 50。
And just so that the program does something noteworthy,
为了让程序做一些值得注意的事情，
let's have it actually print out %i backslash n,
让它实际上打印出 %i 反斜杠 n，
and plug-in that value of n.
并插入 n 的值。
So this is, like, week one stuff, just creating a variable,
所以这就像第一周的东西，只是创建了一个变量，
and printing out its value, just to make sure that we're on the same page.
并打印出它的值，只是为了确保我们理解一致。
So let me do make addresses in my terminal window, enter.
所以让我在我的终端窗口中输入 make addresses，回车。
And when I do dot slash addresses, no surprise.
当我输入点斜杠 addresses 时，不出所料。
I should indeed see the number 50.
我应该看到数字 50。
But let's consider what that actually does inside of the computer
但让我们考虑一下它在计算机内部实际做了什么
now by flipping over, for instance, to this same line of code,
现在，例如，翻转到同一行代码，
and translating it into this same grid.
并将其翻译成相同的网格。
So here's a grid of memory, and I don't necessarily
所以这是一个内存网格，我并不一定
know where in the computer's memory it's going to end up.
知道它将在计算机内存的哪个位置结束。
So I'm picking spots arbitrarily.
所以我随意选择位置。
But I know that an int, typically, is four bytes on most systems.
但我知道，在大多数系统上，一个 int 通常是四个字节。
And so I've used one, two, three, four squares.
所以我用了 1，2，3，4 个方格。
And the first four that I assume are available are down here,
我假设下面这四个是可用的，
and I'm calling this n, and I'm putting the value 50 in it.
我称之为 n，并将值 50 放入其中。
So literally, when you write that line of code, int n equals 50 semicolon,
所以从字面上讲，当你写下那行代码，int n 等于 50 分号，
the computer's doing something like this underneath the hood.
计算机在幕后做了类似的事情。
Might be over here, might be over there, but I've drawn it simply down there.
可能在这里，可能在那里，但我只是简单地把它画在那里。
But that means that that 50 and that variable n,
但这意味着 50 和变量 n，
in particular, live somewhere in the computer's memory.
特别是，存在于计算机的内存中的某个地方。
And where might it live?
它可能住在哪里？
Well, I don't really know.
好吧，我真的不知道。
And frankly, I'm not going to care, ultimately, after today.
坦白地说，从今天开始，我最终不会在乎。
But let me propose that, if all of these bytes are numbered from zero on down,
但让我假设一下，如果所有这些字节都从零开始编号，
maybe this is address OX123, for the sake of discussion.
也许这是地址 OX123，为了讨论方便。
So it's a hexadecimal number, one, two, three.
所以这是一个十六进制数，一，二，三。
It's not 123.
它不是 123。
```
It's one, two, three, but in hexadecimal,
它是 1, 2, 3，但在十六进制中，
just because it's a little easy to say.
只是因为它比较容易说。
But that variable n clearly must live at some address.
但是这个变量 n 显然必须位于某个地址。
So can we maybe see this?
所以我们能看到吗？
Well, it turns out that in C, there is a bit more syntax we can introduce today
结果是，在 C 中，今天我们可以引入更多语法
that actually gives you access to the locations of variables
它实际上让你可以访问变量在计算机内存中的位置
inside of the computer's memory.
在计算机的内存中。
The first of these is literally an ampersand,
第一个是真正的与符号，
and you might pronounce that the address of operator.
你可以把它读作取地址运算符。
Using a single ampersand, you can actually ask the computer
使用一个单独的与符号，你实际上可以问计算机
at what address is this variable.
这个变量位于哪个地址。
And then the asterisk here might be known
然后这里的星号可能被称为
as the dereference operator, which allows you to take an address
解引用运算符，它允许你获取一个地址
and go to it, kind of like following a map.
并转到它，就像在跟着地图走一样。
X marks the spot.
X 标明了位置。
The star will take you to that location in memory,
星号会带你到内存中的那个位置，
so you can see what's actually there.
这样你就可以看到那里究竟是什么。
So what do I mean by that?
我指的是什么？
Well, let me go back over to VS Code here, and let me go ahead
好吧，让我回到 VS Code 这里，让我继续
and change my program to be ever so slightly different, as follows.
将我的程序稍微修改一下，如下所示。
I'm going to still declare n, just as before, to have the value of 50.
我仍然像以前一样声明 n，让它等于 50。
But instead of printing out an integer, per se,
但我不会打印整数，
I'm going to print out an address.
我会打印地址。
And it turns out the format code for that, using printf, is %p.
事实证明，使用 printf 的格式代码是 %p。
And if I want to print out now the address of n,
如果我现在想打印 n 的地址，
recall that I have these two new capabilities, the first of which
请记住，我有这两种新功能，第一个是
is germane.
相关的。
The ampersand will get me the address of n.
与符号将获取 n 的地址。
So let me go back now to VS Code, and let me make a change,
所以现在让我回到 VS Code，让我做一个改变，
whereby I'm going to change the %i to %p,
我将把 %i 更改为 %p，
which is going to show me an address, as opposed to an integer, per se.
这将显示地址，而不是整数本身。
But I need to tell printf what address to show, so I don't want to print out n
但我需要告诉 printf 要显示哪个地址，所以我不想打印 n
because that's literally the number 50.
因为那确实是数字 50。
I want to print out the address of n, like, where is it in memory.
我想打印 n 的地址，比如，它在内存中的哪个位置。
So here I prefix it with an ampersand.
所以这里我在它前面加一个与符号。
And now if I go back into my terminal window, make addresses again,
现在如果我回到我的终端窗口，再次运行 addresses，
dot slash addresses.
点斜杠 addresses。
I'm not going to get as lucky as seeing OX123, probably,
我可能不会像看到 OX123 那样幸运，
because I got even more memory than that in this computer.
因为我的这台电脑有比那更多的内存。
But when I hit enter, I do indeed see OX something.
但当我按下回车键时，我确实看到了 OX 什么东西。
And if I zoom in here, enhance, if you will,
如果我放大这里，增强，如果你愿意的话，
it happens to be at this moment in time, on this server, OX7FFC3A7CFFBC.
它恰好是在这个时刻，在这个服务器上，OX7FFC3A7CFFBC。
So it's a big address.
所以这是一个很大的地址。
That's a really big number if we actually did all of the math.
如果我们真的把所有的数学计算都做一遍，那将是一个非常大的数字。
But who really cares?
但谁在乎呢？
Just the fact that it exists somewhere is the only point for now.
现在唯一重要的是，它确实存在于某个地方。
So this %p symbol that we're passing into printf as a format code is
所以我们传递给 printf 的这个 %p 符号作为格式代码是
leveraging the fact that C supports what are known as pointers.
利用了 C 支持所谓指针这一事实。
So a pointer is really just an address, the address of some variable
所以指针实际上只是一个地址，某个变量的地址
that you can even store in another variable called itself a pointer.
你甚至可以把它存储在另一个名为指针的变量中。
So what do I mean by this?
我指的是什么？
Well, if a pointer is an address, we can start to tinker with this same idea
好吧，如果指针是一个地址，我们可以开始使用同一个想法
as follows.
如下所示。
Let me actually go back to VS Code once more
让我回到 VS Code 这里
and play around with syntax like this.
并尝试使用这样的语法。
So let me still declare a variable called n and set it equal to 50.
所以让我声明一个名为 n 的变量，并将其设置为 50。
But let's actually create an actual pointer,
但让我们实际创建一个真正的指针，
a variable whose purpose in life is not to store a boring number like 50,
一个变量，它的作用不是存储像 50 这样的无聊数字，
but the address of some value.
而是存储某个值的地址。
And so the syntax for that is admittedly weird.
所以它的语法不可否认很奇怪。
If you want p to be a pointer, a variable that stores an address,
如果你希望 p 是一个指针，一个存储地址的变量，
you literally say int star for reasons we'll sort of see.
你会说 int star，原因我们稍后会看到。
And this is different from the star I mentioned earlier for reasons
这与我之前提到的星号不同，原因
we'll also see soon.
我们很快也会看到。
But int star p means, hey compiler, give me
但 int star p 意味着，嘿，编译器，给我
a variable called p, inside of which I can store the address of an integer.
一个名为 p 的变量，我可以在里面存储一个整数的地址。
What address do you want to put in there?
你想把什么地址放进去？
Well, now I can borrow that same syntax from a moment ago.
好吧，现在我可以借用刚才的语法。
I can use ampersand n, which is going to say, hey compiler, give me-- or hey
我可以使用与符号 n，它将说，嘿，编译器，给我——或者嘿
computer, give me the address of n itself.
电脑，给我 n 本身的地址。
Previously, I didn't bother with a variable.
之前，我并没有考虑使用变量。
I just sent the address of n into printf directly.
我只是直接把 n 的地址发送到 printf。
But I can now play with it as follows.
但我现在可以这样玩。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code 这里。
I'll clear my terminal window.
我会清除我的终端窗口。
And let's just play around with two variables.
让我们用两个变量玩一下。
So int star p-- so it's an asterisk, but most people would say star--
所以 int star p——它是一个星号，但大多数人会说 star——
equals the address of n.
等于 n 的地址。
And now, I can just tweak line seven ever so slightly.
现在，我可以稍微调整一下第七行。
Instead of printing out in duplicate ampersand n,
而不是重复打印与符号 n，
I can literally just pass in p for pointer.
我实际上可以直接传递 p 来作为指针。
So I've not done anything really that interesting, other than add a variable,
所以我并没有做任何真正有趣的事情，除了添加一个变量，
but just to show you the syntax via which
但只是为了向你展示语法，通过它
you can create a variable whose purpose in life
你可以创建一个变量，它的作用是
is to store one of these addresses.
存储这些地址之一。
So let me go ahead and now and do make addresses once more.
所以现在让我继续运行 addresses。
Dot slash addresses.
点斜杠 addresses。
And we should see, indeed, pretty much the same idea, the address
我们应该会看到，确实，几乎相同的概念，地址
at which n happens to be, now that I've recompiled and actually run my code.
n 恰好位于那里，因为我已经重新编译并实际运行了我的代码。
But it gets a little more interesting than that.
但它比这更有趣。
I can do one more thing when it comes to my computer's memory.
在涉及到我的计算机内存时，我可以做一件事情。
In VS Code here, let me clear my terminal again, and let me see
在 VS Code 这里，让我再次清除我的终端，让我看看
if I can perhaps reverse this process.
我是否可以反转这个过程。
If n is 50, and p is storing the address of n,
如果 n 是 50，而 p 存储着 n 的地址，
```
wouldn't it be interesting if I could somehow express, go to the address of n
如果我能以某种方式表达，去到 n 的地址，那不是很有趣吗？
and tell me what is there.
并告诉我那里有什么。
So to do that, I'm just kind of undoing all of the intellectual work
为了做到这一点，我正在撤销所有智力工作
I'm doing here.
我在这里做。
But if I want to print out an integer at some location, I can go back to %i,
但如果我想在某个位置打印一个整数，我可以回到 %i，
just print an integer as always.
像往常一样打印一个整数。
But p now is storing the address of someplace.
但 p 现在存储的是某个地方的地址。
It is the treasure map, so to speak.
它可以算是藏宝图。
So if I want to go where X marks the spot,
所以，如果我想去到 X 标注的地方，
the syntax for that I claimed a moment ago is star p.
我刚才说过的语法是 star p。
So star p means go to that address.
所以 star p 的意思是去到那个地址。
Don't print the address, go to that address,
不要打印地址，去到那个地址，
and show me what's inside of the computer's memory there.
并向我展示那里计算机内存中的内容。
So now, if I go into my terminal and do make addresses,
所以现在，如果我进入我的终端并执行 make addresses，
and do dot slash addresses, what should I see on the screen when I hit enter?
并执行 dot slash addresses，当我按回车键时，我应该在屏幕上看到什么？
50.
50。
So I indeed see now 50.
所以我现在确实看到了 50。
Now, here's where it's an unfortunate choice of syntax
现在，这里 C 语言作者几十年前选择了一个不太好的语法
from the authors of C decades ago.
从几十年前的 C 语言作者那里。
Clearly, I'm using star in two different locations.
很明显，我在两个不同的位置使用了 star。
And suffice it to say, it doesn't represent multiplication
可以这么说，它不代表乘法
in either of them.
在任何一个中都不代表。
It's being used to represent addresses somehow.
它被用来以某种方式表示地址。
When, on line six, I specify a data type like int,
当在第六行，我指定一个数据类型，例如 int，
and then I have a star, and then the name of a variable,
然后我有一个星号，然后是一个变量的名称，
that is the syntax for declaring a pointer, for declaring
这就是声明指针的语法，用于声明
a variable that will store an address.
一个将存储地址的变量。
What address?
什么地址？
Well, ampersand n, whatever that is, OX something.
嗯，ampersand n，无论它是什么，OX 等等。
When you do a star and then the name of a pointer without specifying a type,
当你使用星号，然后是指针的名称，而没有指定类型时，
this just means, go there.
这仅仅意味着，去到那里。
So the star clearly is related to addresses.
所以，星号明显与地址相关。
It's unfortunate that it's the same symbol.
不幸的是，它使用的是同一个符号。
It would have been nice if they picked maybe a different symbol
如果他们能选择一个不同的符号
of punctuation.
标点符号就好了。
But they mean slightly different things in that context.
但在那个语境中，它们的意思略有不同。
On line six, we're declaring the pointer,
在第六行，我们正在声明指针，
declaring a variable called p that's going to point to an integers location.
声明一个名为 p 的变量，它将指向一个整数的位置。
But when I say star p, that means go to that actual location.
但当我使用 star p 时，意味着去到实际位置。
So just try to keep that in mind, even though it's ever so slightly subtly
所以，请牢记这一点，即使它非常细微
different.
不同。
So what's going on then inside of the computer's actual memory?
那么，计算机实际内存中发生了什么呢？
Well, let's consider that in pictorial form again.
嗯，让我们再次用图像形式来考虑一下。
So even though I've written the pointer in this way,
所以，即使我用这种方式写了指针，
int then a space, then star p equals ampersand n semicolon, that
int，然后一个空格，然后是 star p 等于 ampersand n 分号，
is the conventional way.
这是传统方式。
That's how you'll see it on most websites, most textbooks.
你将在大多数网站和教科书中看到这种方式。
Technically speaking, I will admit that it might actually
从技术角度来说，我承认，它实际上可能
be easier to understand if you actually move
更容易理解，如果你实际上移动
the asterisk a little to the left, because this makes, visually,
星号稍微向左一点，因为这样从视觉上看，
I think, it even more clear that int star is the type of the variable p, as
我认为，它更加清楚地表明 int star 是变量 p 的类型，
opposed to the star being somehow attached to the variable name itself.
而不是星号以某种方式与变量名本身相关联。
However, you might also see it written with a space on either side, which
然而，你也可以看到它在两边都写着空格，这
I don't think really helps anyone.
我认为对任何人都没有帮助。
But the point is that white space does not matter in this context.
但关键是，在这种情况下空格并不重要。
And the conventional way is to do it by prefixing
传统的方式是，在变量名前面添加
the variable's name with the star.
星号。
And this avoids getting into trouble when you
这样可以避免你在
declare multiple variables at a time.
一次声明多个变量时遇到麻烦。
But if it helps you to think about it, you can think of it as int star
但如果你觉得这样做有帮助，你可以把它看作 int star
as being the type.
作为类型。
It's not just an int, per se.
它不只是一个 int，本身。
So with that said, let's consider now the canvas of computer's memory inside
所以，有了这些，让我们现在考虑一下计算机内存的画布，在
of which we're storing n, and now, p.
其中我们存储了 n，以及现在的 p。
So previously, I proposed that n is maybe, yeah,
所以，之前我提出 n 可能，是的，
maybe it's done in the bottom right hand corner of the screen.
可能它在屏幕的右下角。
So n is storing the number 50 here.
所以，n 这里存储了数字 50。
But technically, n lives somewhere.
但从技术上说，n 存在于某个地方。
And for simplicity, I'm going to claim it's at OX123, rather than the bigger
为了简单起见，我将声称它位于 OX123，而不是我们之前看到的更大的
actual address we just saw.
实际地址。
But what about p?
但 p 呢？
Well, p itself is another variable that I declared separately,
嗯，p 本身是另一个我单独声明的变量，
so it's got to live somewhere in the computer's memory.
所以它必须存在于计算机的内存中的某个地方。
And it turns out, by convention, pointers take up more space.
事实证明，根据惯例，指针占用更多空间。
They typically use eight bytes nowadays, rather than just four.
现在它们通常使用 8 个字节，而不是只有 4 个。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Well, if you've got eight bytes, you can count even higher.
嗯，如果你有 8 个字节，你可以数到更高的数字。
You can have even more addresses.
你可以拥有更多的地址。
You can have more memory in your Mac, your PC, and phone.
你的 Mac、PC 和手机可以有更多的内存。
That's a good thing.
这是一件好事。
So pointers tend to be eight bytes, which
所以，指针往往是 8 个字节，
is why I've used eight squares on the screen here.
这就是我在这里在屏幕上使用 8 个方格的原因。
But what is actually p storing?
但 p 实际上存储的是什么？
Well, it's just storing a number.
嗯，它只是存储了一个数字。
Yes, it's technically an integer, but that integer
是的，从技术上讲它是一个整数，但那个整数
is itself should be thought of as the address of some other value.
本身应该被认为是另一个值的地址。
So n is down here at OX123. p is up here at who knows what address.
所以 n 在这里，位于 OX123。p 在那里，谁知道是什么地址。
Doesn't matter for the sake of discussion,
为了讨论方便，
but its value, what it's storing with its pattern of 64 bits
但它的值，它用 64 位的模式存储的内容
is apparently OX123.
显然是 OX123。
So how does this help us?
所以，这如何帮助我们呢？
Well, if you think about this a little more abstractly, who
嗯，如果你抽象地想一想，谁
cares about what else is going on in the computer's memory?
会关心计算机内存中其他发生了什么？
It actually tends to be helpful to think about this pictorially
实际上，以图像形式思考这一点往往很有帮助
as being a little something like this.
就像这样。
At the end of the day, you and I, even when
最终，你和我，即使当
we start writing code in C that uses pointers,
我们开始用 C 语言编写使用指针的代码时，
generally, you and I are never going to care about the actual addresses.
通常情况下，你和我永远不会关心实际地址。
Even though I showed you OX7 something, that's
即使我给你展示了OX7的某些东西，那也是
not generally useful information.
通常无用的信息。
It's suffices to know that it exists somewhere,
只要知道它存在于某个地方就够了，
and let the computer figure out how to get there.
让计算机想办法找到它。
And so very often when talking about pointers and addresses more generally,
因此，在谈论指针和地址时，
people actually abstract them away, so to speak.
人们实际上会抽象掉它们，可以说是这样。
So instead of literally writing on the screen
所以，与其在屏幕上直接写
or the whiteboard when discussing this, OX123, what the actual address is,
或在讨论时写白板，OX123，实际地址是什么，
who cares what it is?
谁在乎它是什么？
It suffices that it's a value that leads me to the other value
只要它是一个能带我找到另一个值的变量就够了，
that I care about, sort of the treasure map, as I described it earlier.
我关心的值，就像我之前描述的那样，就像藏宝图。
So let's now connect this maybe a little more metaphorically.
现在让我们更形象地连接一下。
So Carter, maybe here you might have noticed
卡特，也许你可能已经注意到
that we've had for a while now these two mailboxes on the stage.
我们现在在舞台上已经有了这两个邮箱一段时间了。
So this white one here is labeled p to represent our pointer variable.
这个白色的邮箱上标着p，代表我们的指针变量。
Carter's is labeled n, representing our actual integer.
卡特的是标着n，代表我们的实际整数。
And what's really kind of going on here is
实际上发生的事情是
that, if I were to access the value inside of p,
如果我要访问p内部的值，
much like we saw it up here, that's like opening this up and figuring out
就像我们在上面看到的，就像打开它，弄清楚
what the actual value is.
实际值是什么。
Now, this itself is a little arcane.
现在，这本身有点神秘。
OX123.
OX123。
And so if we actually do this a little more metaphorically,
因此，如果我们用更形象的方式来做这件事，
we can maybe do this and point our way, if you don't mind.
我们可以这样做，并指向我们的方向，如果你不介意。
So here we have a big pointer.
所以这里有一个大的指针。
Oh, forgive me.
哦，原谅我。
I guess we'll use this one here.
我想我们会用这个。
OK.
好的。
So we have this big pointer that's essentially
所以我们有一个大的指针，它本质上
pointing at the location in memory that we care about, be it OX123,
指向我们关心的内存位置，无论是OX123，
or something else.
还是其他东西。
And then if we dereference this, that is, use the star notation,
然后，如果我们解引用它，也就是说，使用星号符号，
star p, that's like asking Carter to go to that location,
星号p，就像让卡特去那个位置，
open up the mailbox, and voila.
打开邮箱，瞧。
What value do you have there?
你那里有什么值？
Voila.
瞧。
Maybe a big round of applause for Carter for having
也许我们可以为卡特鼓掌，因为他
practiced this beforehand with me.
事先和我练习过。
All right.
好的。
That was mostly just an excuse to use the foam fingers today.
这主要只是今天用泡沫手指的借口。
But with that said, that's hopefully a helpful metaphor,
但话说回来，这希望能成为一个有用的比喻，
honestly, because these pointers, these addresses actually
说实话，因为这些指针，这些地址实际上
tend to be among the more arcane topics in C
往往是C语言中比较神秘的主题之一，
that, even if things are kind of clicking right now, as soon as you
即使现在一切都很好，一旦你
start writing code involving addresses, it's
开始编写涉及地址的代码，这
easy to get lost in some of the details.
很容易迷失在一些细节中。
But metaphorically, these mailboxes are meant
但从比喻的角度来看，这些邮箱代表的其实是
to represent, really, what's going on.
实际发生的事情。
Mailboxes in the physical human world have addresses.
现实世界中的邮箱都有地址。
I can go to that address, open it up, and then I can go to another address
我可以去那个地址，打开它，然后我可以去另一个地址
by following that treasure map, if you will, or pictorially here,
通过跟随那张藏宝图，如果你愿意，或者在这里的图片中，
the arrow that's pointing from one location to another.
指向从一个位置到另一个位置的箭头。
So even though it's very weird syntax with ampersands, and asterisks,
所以，即使它使用符号、星号等，语法非常奇怪，
and the like, it's just addresses in memory,
等等，它只是内存中的地址，
much like mailboxes in the real world.
就像现实世界中的邮箱一样。
So with that said, let's maybe begin to take off certain training
也就是说，我们现在开始重新学习一下字符串，
wheels by revisiting what strings are, as we've been using them thus far.
就像我们一直在使用的那样。
So here's a line of code in C that we've been using since week one,
这是一行C语言代码，我们从第一周就开始使用它了，
really, where I declare a string variable called s, and set it equal to,
实际上，我声明了一个叫做s的字符串变量，并将它设置为等于，
quote unquote, hi.
引号引起来，“hi”。
Now, technically "hi" is three letters, or two letters in a punctuation symbol.
现在，从技术上讲，“hi”是三个字母，或者说是两个字母加一个标点符号。
But how many bytes is that string taking up?
但是这个字符串占用了多少字节？
Is it one, two, three, or was it--
是一个、两个、三个，还是说——
I'm seeing it here.
我在这里看到了。
It's four.
是四个。
Why?
为什么？
Yeah, there's always a null character that, even though you don't see it
是的，始终有一个空字符，即使你没有看到它
on the screen, that is what terminates every string, we claimed, a while back.
在屏幕上，这就是我们之前声称的，结束每个字符串的东西。
So if I were to draw this maybe "hi" ends up
所以，如果我要画出这个，也许“hi”最终会
in the computer's memory down here, bottom right hand corner.
出现在计算机的内存中，在右下角。
But it is indeed four bytes, not just three
但实际上是四个字节，不仅仅是三个
because, secretly, there's always been that null character,
因为，秘密地，始终存在那个空字符，
even though we as programmers don't often
即使我们作为程序员并不经常
have to type it explicitly ourselves.
必须自己显式地输入它。
That's what the double quotes do for us.
这就是双引号为我们做的。
It terminates the string with that null character.
它用空字符结束字符串。
Now, recall from week two when we talked about arrays,
现在，回想一下第二周我们谈论数组的时候，
we started playing around with strings as really
我们开始把字符串视为真正的
just being arrays of characters.
字符数组。
So we call them a string, but we could treat them as arrays of char,
所以我们称它们为字符串，但我们可以把它们视为字符数组，
so to speak.
可以说是这样。
So if the string was called s, s bracket zero would give us the first char,
所以，如果字符串被称为s，s方括号0会给我们第一个字符，
s bracket one the second, s bracket two the third.
s方括号1是第二个，s方括号2是第三个。
And if you're really curious, s bracket three
如果你真的好奇，s方括号3
would give you the last hidden null character,
会给你最后一个隐藏的空字符，
which we saw on the screen as just a zero
我们在屏幕上看到的就是一个零
when we printed it out, while tinkering with some actual code.
当我们在调试一些实际代码时，打印它出来。
But technically, today, logically, it would
但从技术上讲，今天，逻辑上，它会
seem that it's also true that H-I exclamation
看起来它也确实如此，H-I感叹号
point and the null character must clearly live at some address.
点和空字符必须存在于某个地址。
They must clearly live in their own mailbox, so to speak.
他们必须存在于自己的邮箱中，可以说是这样。
So maybe, for the sake of discussion, this H today is at OX123.
所以，为了讨论起见，今天的H可能在OX123。
But recall that arrays are characterized by contiguousness from left to right.
但请记住，数组的特点是从左到右连续。
So if H is at OX123, it must be the case that I is at OX124, I is at 125,
所以，如果H在OX123，那么I一定在OX124，I在125，
and the null character is at OX126 because those are one byte apart.
而空字符在 OX126 处，因为它们之间相差一个字节。
And I deliberately chose numbers here where,
我特意在这里选择了数字，
whether it's decimal or hexadecimal, it doesn't matter.
无论是十进制还是十六进制，都没有关系。
These differ by just one byte themselves.
它们本身只相差一个字节。
So that's what implies that they're indeed
所以这意味着它们确实是
adjacent, or contiguous in memory.
相邻的，或者在内存中是连续的。
But what is s then?
那么 s 是什么呢？
When I declared s to be a string, what is
当我声明 s 是一个字符串时，是什么
it that's been going in s all of this time
一直都在 s 里面呢？
if, clearly, s is actually this thing here?
如果，很明显，s 实际上就是这里的东西呢？
Well, strings have kind of been a white lie for a few weeks
好吧，字符串在过去几周里一直都是一个善意的谎言
because s itself, technically, is a pointer.
因为 s 本身，从技术上来说，是一个指针。
s is the address of this string.
s 是这个字符串的地址。
So the string is somewhere in memory, but s
所以这个字符串在内存中的某个地方，但是 s
itself is a separate variable that gives you
本身是一个独立的变量，它给你
a clue as how to find all of those characters in memory.
一个线索，告诉你如何在内存中找到所有这些字符。
So if you had to guess just intuitively now,
所以如果你现在必须凭直觉猜测，
if this is the string actually in memory, that is, this
如果这是实际存储在内存中的字符串，也就是说，这个
is the array of chars in memory, what would logically
是内存中的字符数组，那么从逻辑上来说，
make sense to put as the value of s?
把什么作为 s 的值是有意义的？
A pointer.
一个指针。
Specifically?
具体来说呢？
A pointer to h.
指向 h 的指针。
And how would I express that?
我该如何表达呢？
What's the actual value?
实际值是什么呢？
OX123 might very well suffice as the value here of s.
OX123 很可能足以作为 s 的值。
Now, why might that be?
现在，为什么可能是这样呢？
Well, that essentially gives you enough information
嗯，这实际上给了你足够的关于
to find the beginning of the string, "hi" in this case.
字符串开头的信息，在这种情况下是 "hi"。
Now, you might think, well, wait a minute.
现在，你可能会想，等等。
How does it know about the second character and the third character?
它怎么知道第二个字符和第三个字符呢？
But now, if you kind of rewind in time, oh, wait a minute,
但是现在，如果你把时间倒流一下，哦，等等，
maybe now the null character actually makes even more sense from week two.
也许现在空字符从第二周开始就更有意义了。
Why?
为什么呢？
Because if s technically storing the location
因为如果 s 从技术上来说存储的是
of the beginning of the string, someone's
字符串开头的地址，那么有人
got to keep track of where the string ends, presumably.
必须追踪字符串的结尾，应该是这样。
And that's effectively the string itself because humans decided decades ago,
而这实际上就是字符串本身，因为人类在几十年前就决定了，
let's just null terminate every string with a special
让我们用一个特殊的空字符来终止每个字符串，
so character, zero, all zero bits, eight zero bits, specifically.
也就是零，所有位都是零，八个零位，具体来说。
But and that's enough information.
但这已经足够的信息了。
The sort of treasure map leads you to the beginning of the string,
这种“藏宝图”可以把你带到字符串的开头，
and then you can use a for loop, a while loop,
然后你可以使用 for 循环、while 循环，
or whatever to walk through the string, and that's what printf does.
或者其他方法来遍历字符串，这就是 printf 的作用。
And you just stop as soon as you see that null character.
一旦你看到空字符，你就停止。
So this then is what a string actually is.
所以，这就是字符串的真实面目。
s is and has always been, since week one, a pointer, so to speak,
s 从第一周开始，一直都是，可以这样说，一个指针，
that actually refers to the start of that array of characters.
它实际上指向字符数组的开头。
And frankly, again, who cares about the OX123 specifics?
坦率地说，我们再次强调，谁在乎 OX123 的具体细节呢？
We can abstract that away and actually just treat
我们可以将其抽象出来，实际上只需将
s as, literally, an arrow that points to the beginning of that string
s 视为，字面意思上，一个指向字符串开头的箭头
because it will be rare that we actually care about where this thing
因为我们很少会真正关心这个东西
physically is in the computer's memory.
在计算机内存中的物理位置。
Now, before we see this in code, any questions on this revelation?
现在，在我们看到代码之前，关于这个揭示有任何问题吗？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: Have pointers gotten larger as computer memories
听众：随着几十年来计算机内存的增加，指针也变大了嗎？
have increased over the decades?
在几十年来内存增加的情况下？
SPEAKER 1: Yes.
演讲者 1：是的。
Have pointers gotten larger as computers memory has increased over the decades?
随着几十年来计算机内存的增加，指针也变大了嗎？
Short answer, yes.
简短的回答是，是的。
Like, back in my day, we were limited to, like, two gigabytes
就像，在我那个年代，我们被限制在，大约，两个吉字节
of memory total.
的总内存。
Well, why two?
嗯，为什么是两个呢？
Well, if you had 32-bit memory, or if you use 32 bits
嗯，如果你有 32 位内存，或者如果你使用 32 位
to represent addresses, a.k.a. four bytes, as was conventional,
来表示地址，也就是四个字节，就像传统上那样，
you can count recall as high as 4 billion values.
你可以统计到高达 40 亿个值。
But generally, numbers are both negative and positive, so that halves it.
但通常情况下，数字既有负数也有正数，所以这将它减半。
So the reason decades ago, computers, PCs, Macs
所以几十年前，计算机、PC、Mac
could have no more than two gigabytes of memory was because, literally,
只能拥有不超过两个吉字节的内存，是因为，从字面上来说，
the integers being used, the pointers being used
所使用的整数，所使用的指针
were only four bits, that is 32 bits.
只有四位，也就是 32 位。
Sorry, four bytes, that is, 32 bits long.
抱歉，是四个字节，也就是 32 位长。
And so you literally could buy more memory.
因此，你可以买更多的内存。
You could buy a third gigabyte, a fourth gigabyte,
你可以买第三个吉字节，第四个吉字节，
but you literally had no way mathematically
但你从数学上来说真的没有办法
to express all of those bigger locations.
来表达所有这些更大的位置。
So it was effectively useless, in that case.
所以，在这种情况下，它实际上是无用的。
In more modern times, computers tend now to use 64 bits, which
在更现代的时代，计算机现在倾向于使用 64 位，这
allows you to count crazy high.
允许你统计到非常高的数字。
And that's more than enough to address bigger chunks of memory.
而且这足以处理更大的内存块。
Really good question.
真是个好问题。
Others on memory thus far.
关于内存还有什么问题？
No, all right.
没有，好的。
Well, let's translate this a bit to code by going back over to VS Code here.
好吧，让我们通过回到 VS Code 来将这段内容翻译成代码。
And let me propose now that we revisit maybe a simpler string
现在，我建议我们重新审视一下更简单的字符串
example, as opposed to these integers.
示例，而不是这些整数。
So let me go ahead and throw away all of this integer related code.
所以，让我继续把所有这些与整数相关的代码都扔掉。
Let me go ahead and, for the moment, include CS50.h
让我继续，暂时，包含 CS50.h
so that we have access to string and other things as in week one.
这样我们就可以像第一周一样访问字符串和其他内容。
And let me do a string s equals quote unquote "HI" in all caps.
让我定义一个字符串 s，等于双引号内的 “HI”，所有字母都大写。
And let me do a simple safety check %s backslash n s,
让我做一次简单的安全检查，%s 反斜杠 n s，
just to make sure everything works as it did in week one.
只是为了确保一切像第一周那样工作。
So make addresses, dot slash addresses, and I should indeed
所以，创建地址，点斜杠地址，我应该确实
see "HI" on the screen.
在屏幕上看到 "HI"。
Well, let's now kind of tinker with what's going on underneath the hood.
好吧，现在让我们仔细看看幕后发生了什么。
And now, things can get a little more memory specific.
现在，事情会变得更具体一些，与内存相关。
So I'm still going to declare s as a string up here.
所以我仍然要在这里声明 s 是一个字符串。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
Instead of printing out the string itself,
与其直接打印字符串本身，
let me actually treat s as the pointer I claim it is.
让我实际将 s 作为我声称的指针处理。
I claim a string is just an address, so I have this new syntax today,
我声称字符串只是一个地址，所以今天我有了这个新的语法，
%p to print out pointers, to print out addresses.
%p 用于打印指针，打印地址。
Let's see what s actually is.
让我们看看 s 实际上是什么。
Let me do make addresses again, dot slash addresses, and there it is.
让我再次执行 make addresses，点斜杠 addresses，它就在那儿。
It's not as simple as OX123, but it is at location OX55C670878004.
它不像 OX123 那样简单，但它位于 OX55C670878004 位置。
All right.
好吧。
Who really cares, specifically?
具体来说，谁会在乎呢？
But if we poke around a bit more, things might make a bit more sense.
但如果我们再探究一下，事情可能就会更清晰一些。
Let's do this.
让我们试试。
Let's also print out the address using %p of, how about the very first
让我们也使用 %p 打印出... 如何... 关于第一个...
character of s.
s 的字符。
So the very first character of is known as s bracket zero.
所以第一个字符被称为 s 方括号零。
We did that in week two, treating a string as an array.
我们在第二周做过，将字符串当作数组处理。
But how do I get the address of a character?
但是如何获得字符的地址？
Well, I have our new symbol today, ampersand.
嗯，今天我们有新符号，取地址符。
So even though this looks like a mouthful, ampersand, s, square bracket,
所以即使看起来很拗口，取地址符、s、方括号，
zero, square bracket, it's just two ideas combined.
零、方括号，它只是将两个想法结合起来。
s bracket zero gives you the first character in the string, s.
s 方括号零会给你字符串 s 中的第一个字符。
And adding an ampersand at the beginning says, tell me what that address is.
在开头添加一个取地址符表示，告诉我那个地址是什么。
So if I recompile this code, make addresses, dot slash addresses,
所以如果我重新编译这段代码，make addresses，点斜杠 addresses，
even if you don't remember the value OX whatever,
即使你不记得 OX 后的值是多少，
what are we going to see on the screen at a higher level?
我们将在屏幕上看到什么呢？
Perhaps the same exact thing.
可能是完全相同的东西。
Why?
为什么？
Well, s is just an address.
嗯，s 只是一个地址。
But what does that mean?
但这意味着什么呢？
Well, it's just the address of its first character.
嗯，它只是第一个字符的地址。
And we saw that per our picture a moment ago.
刚才我们从图中看到过。
So can I see the contiguousness of this?
所以我能看到它的连续性吗？
Well, I'm going to resort to some copy paste just for time's sake,
嗯，为了节省时间，我将使用一些复制粘贴，
even though this is going to look a little silly,
即使看起来有点愚蠢，
and I could certainly use a loop instead.
我当然可以使用循环来代替。
But let me print out the second location, the third location, and heck,
但让我打印出第二个位置、第三个位置，以及...
even the fourth location, whoops, the fourth location of that null character.
第四个位置... 哎呦，第四个位置，那个空字符的第四个位置。
If I now do make addresses again and dot slash addresses, and zoom in,
如果我现在再次执行 make addresses，然后点斜杠 addresses，并放大，
I don't really care about what these are, specifically.
具体来说，我不在乎它们是什么。
But notice the first two are indeed the same because the first represents s.
但请注意，前两个确实是相同的，因为第一个代表 s。
The first represents the first character of s,
第一个代表 s 的第一个字符，
which now I reveal are exactly the same idea.
现在我揭示了它们实际上是同一个概念。
And the next ones are literally just one byte
接下来的几个位置实际上只是相差一个字节
away, ending in five, six, and seven, respectively.
而已，分别以五、六、七结尾。
So again, the numbers in and of themselves
所以，再次强调，数字本身
are not useful, actionable information, but it
并不是有用的、可操作的信息，但它
does let us actually see what's going on underneath the hood.
确实让我们得以一窥幕后的运行机制。
So just to rewind for a moment, let me actually go back to the original
所以，让我先倒回一下，回到最初的
version, where I'm printing out the string itself, using %s.
版本，我使用 %s 打印出字符串本身。
Let me remake addresses to make sure that, OK, it still prints out "HI".
让我重新执行 make addresses 来确保... 好了，它仍然打印出 "HI"。
But what has been going on now all this time?
但一直以来都发生了什么呢？
Well, let me go back to our simple line of code
嗯，让我回到我们从第一周就开始使用的那行简单的代码
that we've been using since week one, which
从第一周开始使用，它
gave us a string called s, setting it equal to the value of "HI".
为我们提供了一个名为 s 的字符串，并将其设置为 "HI" 的值。
Let me propose now that strings were indeed this white lie.
现在让我假设，字符串确实是一种善意的谎言。
And if I can unnecessarily dramatically say,
如果我可以用一种夸张的语调说，
here we take the training wheels off and reveal
现在我们将去掉辅助轮，揭示
that, all this time, string, string is probably, actually, what, technically?
一直以来，字符串，字符串可能实际上... 从技术上讲是什么？
Yeah.
是的。
A char star.
一个字符指针。
That was amazing.
太棒了。
Thank you for that.
谢谢。
So yeah.
所以，是的。
So it's a char star, which admittedly at first glance,
所以它是一个字符指针，不可否认的是，乍一看，
just makes a simple idea look unnecessarily complicated.
它只是让一个简单的想法看起来不必要地复杂。
And that's why in week one, we indeed introduced these training wheels,
这就是为什么在第一周，我们确实引入了这些辅助轮，
whereby we, CS50, invented the datatype called string, just to kind of hide
通过这些辅助轮，我们，CS50，发明了名为字符串的数据类型，只是为了隐藏
this lower level detail.
这个低级细节。
If you will, string for us is an abstraction.
如果你愿意，字符串对我们来说是一种抽象。
Now, that is to say string is not a CS50 specific word.
现在，也就是说，字符串不是 CS50 特定的词语。
Every programmer in the world knows what a string is.
世界上每个程序员都知道字符串是什么。
It is a sequence of characters.
它是一系列字符。
It is an array of characters.
它是一个字符数组。
But in C, technically, decades ago when it was invented,
但在 C 语言中，从技术上讲，几十年前发明 C 语言时，
they didn't think, they didn't decide to create an actual data type called
他们没有想过，他们没有决定创建一个名为
string because, especially if they were among those more comfortable,
字符串的数据类型，因为，特别是如果他们更喜欢使用
char star is equivalent, and it achieves the exact same thing,
字符指针，它等效，并且实现了完全相同的功能，
even though at a glance, we didn't want to start week one with that lower level
即使乍一看，我们不想在第一周就介绍那个低级
detail.
细节。
Question here in front.
前面有个问题。
Sure.
当然。
Can I clarify how the star makes it a string?
我能解释一下星号是如何让它成为字符串的吗？
So we've, up until now, been just calling it a string
所以，到目前为止，我们一直在称之为字符串
so that's s is a string.
所以 s 就是一个字符串。
And that's a sufficient mental model.
这是一个足够的心理模型。
But technically, what is a string?
但从技术上讲，字符串是什么？
I claimed pictorially with my grid of memory
我在我的内存网格上画了图，
that a string is really just an address.
声称字符串实际上只是一个地址。
It's really just the address of its first character.
它实际上只是第一个字符的地址。
I then tried to demonstrate as much in code by using percent p
然后，我尝试使用百分号 p 在代码中演示这一点，
and showing you, literally, s is a value, like, OX something.
并向你展示，实际上，s 是一个值，比如 OX 后面的东西。
And literally, its first character is at that same address, OX something.
实际上，它的第一个字符位于同一个地址，OX 后面的东西。
So here, when I claim that string has never really existed,
所以，这里，当我声称字符串从未真正存在过时，
except within the confines of CS50, technically, the data type of a string
除了在 CS50 的范围内，从技术上讲，字符串的数据类型
is best expressed as char star.
最好表达为字符指针。
Why?
为什么？
Well, a string clearly can't just be a char because a char, by definition,
好吧，字符串显然不能仅仅是一个字符，因为根据定义，
is a single character.
它是一个单字符。
A string, we already know, is a sequence of characters.
我们已经知道，字符串是字符的序列。
But how can you represent a sequence of characters?
但是，如何表示字符序列？
You can call it a char star, which is a different data type that we're
你可以称它为字符星，这是一个我们今天第一次介绍的不同数据类型。
introducing today for the first time.
我们今天第一次介绍。
And the star just means that s itself is not a char.
星号只是表示s本身不是一个字符。
The star means that s is the address of a char.
星号表示s是一个字符的地址。
And by convention, it's the address of the first char in a string.
按照惯例，它是字符串中第一个字符的地址。
So with that said, if I go back to my actual VS Code over here,
所以，说到这里，如果我回到我的VS Code，
I can change, literally, char string to char star s.
我可以改变，实际上，将字符字符串改为字符星s。
I can get rid of the CS50 library, our so-called training wheels,
我可以摆脱CS50库，我们所谓的辅助轮，
which has been the goal for the past few weeks, to put them on initially
这是过去几周的目标，最初使用它们，
and then take them off quite quickly.
然后快速移除它们。
So now this is the same program, and %s is still the same. s is still the same.
所以现在，这还是同一个程序，%s 仍然是一样的。s 也仍然是一样的。
Everything else is still the same.
其他都一样。
All I've done is change, quote unquote, string to,
我所做的只是改变，换句话说，将字符串改为，
quote unquote, char star, which obviates the need for the CS50 library.
换句话说，字符星，这避免了使用CS50库的必要性。
And if I now do make addresses and dot slash addresses,
如果我现在使用make addresses 和 dot slash addresses，
"HI" behaves exactly as it would.
"HI" 的行为和以前一样。
So this is now raw native C code without any training wheels,
所以现在这是原始的本地C代码，没有任何辅助轮，
without any CS50 scaffolding, that just uses these basic building
没有任何CS50支架，它只使用这些基本构建
blocks and primitives.
块和基本类型。
Other questions on this?
还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Could you please clarify why we don't use the end symbol for that
观众：你能解释一下为什么我们不使用结束符号来表示那个
s, as opposed to the other ones?
s，而不是其他符号？
SPEAKER 1: Correct.
演讲者1：没错。
Why don't we use the ampersand symbol for this, though we did earlier?
为什么我们不使用取地址符号来表示这个，虽然我们之前用过？
So in this case, there's no reason for an ampersand
所以，在这种情况下，没有理由使用取地址符号
because the ampersand tells you what the address of a variable is.
因为取地址符号告诉你变量的地址是什么。
I'll concede that it probably would be a little more
我承认，这样做可能会更
consistent for us to do this, which is maybe where your mind is going.
一致，可能这就是你的想法。
Now, never mind the fact that looks even worse, I think, syntactically.
现在，别管它看起来更糟糕，我认为，在语法上。
It's a reasonable instinct, but it turns out
这是一个合理的本能，但事实证明
that two is what the double quotes are doing for you.
双引号为你做的正是这件事。
The C compiler, called Clang, is smart enough
C编译器，叫做Clang，足够聪明
to realize that when it sees double quotes around a sequence of characters,
意识到当它看到字符序列周围的双引号时，
it wants to put the address of that first char in the variable for you.
它希望将第一个字符的地址放在你的变量中。
But when we had a variable like n, which we created,
但是当我们有一个像n这样的变量时，它是我们创建的，
you have to distinguish n from its address.
你必须区分n和它的地址。
So that's why we prefixed n with an ampersand.
所以这就是为什么我们在n前面加上取地址符号。
But the double quotes take care of it for you.
但是双引号为你处理了这件事。
Other questions on these here addresses?
关于这些地址还有其他问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
Well, beyond that, let me propose that we tinker with one other idea
除此之外，我想建议我们修改另一个想法
to see how we actually invented this thing called a string.
看看我们是如何真正发明了这个叫做字符串的东西的。
Well, I claim that string is just char star.
好吧，我认为字符串仅仅是字符星。
You've actually seen this technique before.
你之前已经见过这种技术了。
It was just a week ago that we tinkered with structures, custom data types
就在一周前，我们修改了结构，自定义数据类型
to represent a person.
来表示一个人。
And recall that we had a structure of a name and a number representing
你还记得，我们有一个表示人的结构，其中包含一个姓名和一个数字。
a person.
一个人的结构。
But more importantly, we had this keyword typedef,
但更重要的是，我们有这个关键字typedef，
which defines your own type to be whatever you want.
它定义了你自己的类型，可以是你想要的任何类型。
Now, we used it a little more powerfully last time
现在，我们上次使用它的时候更强大一些
to actually represent a whole structure of a person, having a name,
来真正表示一个人的整个结构，包括姓名，
and having a number.
还有数字。
But at the end of the day, we really just invented our own data type
但归根结底，我们实际上只是发明了自己的数据类型
that we called, obviously, person.
我们称之为，显然是，person。
But and that represented, indeed, this structure.
但是它确实表示了这个结构。
But typedef was really the enabling element there.
但typedef 确实是那里使能的元素。
And so it turns out with typedef, you can create
所以，事实证明，使用typedef，你可以创建
any number of data types of your own.
任意数量的你自己的数据类型。
For instance, if you just really can't get
例如，如果你真的不能理解
the hang of calling an integer an int, you
将整数称为int，你可以
can create your own data type called integer
创建自己的数据类型，称为integer
that itself is a synonym for int, because the way typedef works,
它本身是int的同义词，因为typedef 的工作方式，
even though this one's even simpler than the struct,
即使这个比结构更简单，
is you can read it from right to left.
就是你可以从右往左读它。
This means give me a data type called integer that is actually an int.
这意味着给我一个叫做integer的数据类型，它实际上是一个int。
And that's the same thing that happened a moment ago.
这就是刚才发生的事情。
Give me a data type called person that is actually this whole structure.
给我一个叫做person的数据类型，它实际上是整个结构。
But an integer is even simpler.
但整数更简单。
Now, most people wouldn't do this.
现在，大多数人不会这样做。
This really doesn't create any intellectual enhancement of the data
这并不会真正提高数据的智力水平
types, but you could do it if you really wanted.
类型，但如果你真的想，你可以这样做。
More commonly, and as you'll see this in code in the future,
更常见的是，你将在将来的代码中看到，
would be not just a typedef something like an integer.
不仅仅是typedef像integer这样的东西。
But it turns out, curiously, C has no data type for a byte.
但事实证明，奇怪的是，C没有表示字节的数据类型。
Like, there's no built in obvious way to represent eight bits
就像，没有内置的明显方法来表示8位
and store whatever you want in them.
并将你想要的任何东西存储在其中。
However, you can use what's called a uint8_t, t
但是，你可以使用一个叫做uint8_t的东西，t
which is a data type that comes with C. And frankly, those more comfortable
它是一个C自带的数据类型。坦率地说，那些更习惯
might simply use this data type once you sort of
的人可能会简单地使用这种数据类型，一旦你 sort of
commit to memory that it exists.
记住它存在。
But honestly, for most of us, it's a lot more convenient to think of a byte
但说实话，对我们大多数人来说，将字节
as being its own data type.
视为它自己的数据类型，会方便得多。
When you want to write code that manipulates one or two or more bytes,
当你想要编写操纵一个、两个或更多字节的代码时，
wouldn't it be nice to have a data type called byte?
拥有一个叫做字节的数据类型，难道不很好吗？
So it turns out that you can represent a byte, which is eight bits using
所以，事实证明，你可以使用一个无符号的8位整数来表示一个字节，它有8位。
an unsigned integer with 8 bits.
一个无符号的8位整数。
And this is just a data type that's declared in some other C header file.
而这只是一个在其他C头文件中声明的数据类型。
But long story short, you'll see and use this before long.
但长话短说，你很快就会看到并使用它。
But it's just a synonym to make things a little more user friendly,
但这只是一个同义词，让事情更易于使用，
like person, like string, like byte.
比如人、字符串、字节。
So what is in the CS50 header file, among other things?
那么，除了其他内容，CS50 头文件里有什么？
Literally, this line of code.
实际上，就是这行代码。
This is the single line of code that we deploy
这就是我们在第一周之后部署的单行代码，
in week one onward that teaches Clang to think of the word string
它让 Clang 从第一周开始就将“string”这个词
as being synonymous with char star, so that you all never have to type,
视为与“char star”同义，这样你们就永远不必输入，
or know, or think about char star until, wonderfully, today in week four,
知道或思考“char star”，直到今天，也就是第四周，
a couple of weeks later instead.
也就是几周之后才需要。
So that's all we've been doing.
所以，这就是我们一直在做的事情。
That is the technical implementation of the training wheels.
这就是辅助轮的技术实现。
It's just using a custom data type in this way.
它只是用这种方式使用自定义数据类型。
So how about one other maybe pair of examples here with our addresses,
所以，我们再来看看地址的另一个例子，
such that we can tinker a little bit further?
这样我们就可以进一步调整一下？
It turns out that, once everything in the world
事实证明，一旦世界上的一切
is addressable using these pointers, like using numeric addresses
都可以使用这些指针寻址，就像使用数值地址
to represent where things are in memory, you can actually
来表示事物在内存中的位置，你实际上
do something called pointer arithmetic.
可以做一些叫做指针运算的事情。
And here, too, we the programmers generally
在这里，我们程序员通常
don't care what the specific values are, but we care that they do exist.
并不关心具体的值是什么，但我们关心它们是否存在。
And if they do exist, we can maybe do some arithmetic on them
如果它们存在，我们就可以对它们进行一些运算
and add one to go to the next byte, add two to go to the next, next byte,
加 1 跳到下一个字节，加 2 跳到下下个字节，
add three to go to the next, next, net byte, and so forth.
加 3 跳到下下下个字节，以此类推。
So pointer arithmetic literally refers to doing math on addresses.
所以，指针运算实际上是指对地址进行数学运算。
So how do we translate this into something actionable?
那么，我们如何将它转化为可操作的东西呢？
Let me actually go back to VS Code here, and let
让我回到 VS Code，然后让
me propose that we do something like the following.
我建议我们做以下事情。
I'm going to throw away my first printf here.
我将丢弃第一个 printf。
And I'm instead going to print out this string character by character,
我将逐个字符地打印出这个字符串，
just like we did in week two.
就像我们在第二周做的那样。
Let me go ahead and call printf, pass in %c for a single char, backslash n,
让我调用 printf，传入 %c 用于单个字符，反斜杠 n，
comma, and now I want to print out the first character in s.
逗号，现在我想要打印出 s 中的第一个字符。
Using array notation, what do I type to print the first character in s?
使用数组表示法，我应该输入什么才能打印出 s 中的第一个字符？
Yep, over here.
没错，在这里。
s bracket zero.
s 中括号 0。
So s bracket zero gives me the first character in s.
所以 s 中括号 0 给出了 s 中的第一个字符。
And let me copy paste just for demonstration sake
为了演示，让我复制粘贴
here inside of my same curly braces, and print out
到我相同的括号里，打印出
the second char, and the third.
第二个字符和第三个字符。
And I don't care about the null character.
我不关心空字符。
I just want to print the string itself for now.
我现在只想打印字符串本身。
So even though this is jumping through way more hoops than just using %s
所以，虽然这比直接使用 %s 打印整个字符串要复杂得多，
and print the whole thing at once, it's again, just demonstrating how we can,
但它再次展示了我们如何，
at a lower level, manipulate these strings.
在更低层次上，操作这些字符串。
So let me do make addresses, dot slash addresses.
所以，让我做 make addresses，点斜杠 addresses。
And yet again, we see, somewhat stupidly, one
又一次，我们看到，有点愚蠢的是，一行
per line, H-I exclamation point.
一个字符，H-I 感叹号。
I can, of course fix that by getting rid of this.
当然，我可以通过去掉这个来解决。
I can get rid of this, and I can leave the last backslash n.
我可以去掉这个，并且保留最后一个反斜杠 n。
So let's just make it a look a little prettier.
所以，让我们让它看起来更漂亮一些。
Make addresses, dot slash addresses, enter,
Make addresses，点斜杠 addresses，回车，
and I can print it out all on one line.
然后我可以将它全部打印在一行上。
But now using pointer notation, it turns out
但是现在使用指针表示法，事实证明
we can do one other thing, which admittedly, for now,
我们还可以做另外一件事，虽然现在，
is going to feel like unnecessary complexity.
感觉有点过于复杂了。
But it's actually a really helpful tool to add to our toolkit, so to speak,
但它实际上是一个非常有用的工具，可以添加到我们的工具箱中，
whereby I could instead do this.
因此，我还可以这样做。
To print out the first character in s, yes, I can treat it as an array
要打印出 s 中的第一个字符，是的，我可以把它看作一个数组
and get the zeroth index.
然后获取索引 0。
However, what is s? s is just the address of a string.
但是，s 是什么呢？s 只是字符串的地址。
What does that mean? s is the address of the first char in the string.
这是什么意思？s 是字符串中第一个字符的地址。
So if I do star s, what's that going to print?
那么，如果我执行星号 s，它会打印什么呢？
Presumably h, right?
可能是 h，对吧？
Because if the first character in s is h, then star s will go to that address
因为如果 s 中的第一个字符是 h，那么星号 s 会跳转到那个地址
and show me what's actually there.
然后显示实际存在的内容。
And let me go ahead and do this again.
让我继续做这件事。
Let me copy paste twice and then tweak this a little bit.
让我复制粘贴两次，然后稍微修改一下。
I want to go to the next byte over.
我想跳到下一个字节。
Well, I could do s bracket one.
好吧，我可以使用 s 中括号 1。
All right, but I could instead go to s plus one.
好吧，但我也可以跳转到 s 加 1。
And I could instead go to s plus two, thereby
我也可以跳转到 s 加 2，从而
doing what we're calling pointer arithmetic, math on addresses.
进行我们称之为指针运算的操作，也就是对地址进行运算。
And now, if I go ahead and rerun make addresses, dot slash addresses, voila.
现在，如果我运行 make addresses，点斜杠 addresses，瞧。
Whoops, I forgot my backslash n.
哎呀，我忘记了反斜杠 n。
Let's fix that just to be tidy.
让我们把它修复一下，让它更整洁。
Dot slash addresses, voila.
点斜杠 addresses，瞧。
There is our "HI".
这就是我们的“HI”。
Now, this is not how a normal person would print out a string,
现在，这并不是正常人打印字符串的方式，
but it does go to show you that there's not really been any magic.
但这确实向你展示了，实际上并没有什么魔法。
Like, these characters are just where we predicted they would be.
就像，这些字符恰好位于我们预测它们应该出现的位置。
And now that you have this star notation, the dereference operator,
现在你有了这个星号表示法，也就是解除引用运算符，
which means go there, you have the ability to access individual values.
这意味着跳转到那里，你就可以访问单个值。
You even have the ability to ask where those things are by using ampersands,
你甚至可以使用取地址符来询问这些事物在何处，
as well.
也是。
But it turns out that the reason that we introduced the array syntax first
但事实证明，我们首先引入数组语法的原因
is that the array syntax is what the world would
是因为数组语法是世界所称的
call syntactic sugar for exactly this.
语法糖，用于实现这一点。
When you say s bracket zero, the compiler is essentially doing star s
当你使用 s 中括号 0 时，编译器本质上是在执行星号 s
and saving you the trouble.
并且为你省去了麻烦。
When you do s bracket one, the compiler is essentially
当你使用 s 中括号 1 时，编译器本质上是在
saving you the trouble of doing star, in parentheses, s plus one,
为你省去了执行星号，在括号中，s 加 1 的麻烦，
and same for the third char, as well.
并且第三个字符也是如此。
So all this time, pointers have been there underneath the hood.
所以一直以来，指针都在幕后。
They are what allow us to go to very specific memory locations.
它们允许我们访问非常具体的内存位置。
They are going to be what allow us soon to start manipulating files,
它们将很快让我们开始操作文件，
whether it's photographs of stress balls, or CSI style content.
无论是压力球的照片，还是犯罪现场调查风格的内容。
But for now, I think we should take our 10 minute break where whoopie pies will
但现在，我认为我们应该休息10分钟，期间将会供应松饼。
now be served in the transept.
它们将在横厅供应。
See you in 10.
10分钟后见。
All right.
好的。
So we are back, and we've clearly drawn too much attention to the stress balls
我们回来了，很明显，我们对压力球给予了过多的关注，
today because now we're all out of these and whoopie pies.
因为现在压力球和松饼都用完了。
But more next week.
但下周会有更多。
In the meantime, though, we thought we'd now
同时，我们认为现在应该
use some of these new building blocks, this idea of being able to manipulate
使用一些新的构建模块，也就是能够操作
underlying addresses, to revisit a couple of problems
底层地址，重新审视一些我们之前
that we kind of swept under the rug previously
暂时搁置的问题。
by avoiding these problems altogether.
通过完全避免这些问题。
So by that, I mean this.
我的意思是。
Let me go over to VS Code.
让我打开 VS Code。
And let me create another example called compare.c,
让我创建一个名为 compare.c 的另一个示例，
whose purpose in life in a moment is going to be to compare values
它的作用是比较值，
in kind of a very weak one way, too.
而且以一种非常弱的方式比较。
So let me go ahead and include CS50.h.
所以让我添加 CS50.h 头文件。
Let me go ahead and include standard io.h.
让我添加 stdio.h 头文件。
Let me do int main void, no command line arguments.
让我编写 int main void 函数，没有命令行参数。
And in here, let me just get two integers using getint as follows.
这里，让我使用 getint 获取两个整数，如下所示。
So getint, and we'll ask for i.
使用 getint 获取 i。
Let's go ahead and get int and ask for j,
让我们获取 j，
just so that we have two things to compare.
这样我们就有两个要比较的东西了。
And then I'm going to do something super simple.
然后我要做一件非常简单的事情。
So if i equals, equals j, then let's print out,
如果 i 等于 j，那么打印输出，
as we actually did in the past, same backslash n.
就像我们以前做的那样，相同的后斜杠 n。
Else, if they're not the same, let's of course, print out, for instance,
否则，如果它们不相同，那么打印输出，例如，
different.
不同。
So super simple program that we used the first time around, really,
这是一个非常简单的程序，我们在第一次的时候使用过它，
just to demonstrate conditionals.
只是为了演示条件语句。
But now, we'll use it to tease apart some subtleties.
但现在，我们将用它来揭示一些微妙之处。
So let me go ahead and compile this with make compare.
让我们用 make compare 命令编译这个程序。
Dot slash compare.
运行 compare 程序。
And we'll compare one and one for i and j respectively.
我们将分别比较 i 和 j 的值 1 和 1。
Those are, of course, the same.
当然，它们是相同的。
Let's compare one and two.
让我们比较 1 和 2。
Those are, of course, different.
当然，它们是不同的。
So long story short, this program seems to work,
总之，这个程序似乎可以正常工作，
and we won't dwell much further on it.
我们不会再深入研究它。
But let's consider for a moment what's going on inside of the computer's
但让我们思考一下，当代码在计算机中执行时，
memory when that code is executed.
内存中发生了什么。
So here's my canvas of memory.
这是我的内存画布。
Maybe i ends up over here.
i 可能在这里。
Maybe j ends up over here.
j 可能在这里。
Each of them I've drawn as four squares because integers are typically
我将它们都画成了四个方块，因为整数通常
four bytes, or 32 bits.
是四个字节，或 32 位。
So i has the value 50 here. i has the value 50.
所以 i 在这里的值是 50，i 的值也是 50。
So I accidentally typed one and one, but assume
我无意中输入了 1 和 1，但假设
that I had typed 50 in both cases.
我输入的都是 50。
They both live at these two separate locations.
它们都位于这两个不同的位置。
All right.
好的。
So that's all fine and good.
这些都很好。
And when we compare them, of course, 50 and 50, or one and one
当我们比较它们时，当然，50 和 50，或者 1 和 1
are, in fact, the exact same.
实际上是一样的。
But what if we actually compare different types of values?
但是如果我们比较不同类型的值呢？
Let me go back into VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code 中。
And instead of integers, let's still, using the CS50 library,
让我们使用 CS50 库，但不再使用整数，
maybe use some strings instead.
而是使用一些字符串。
So let me go ahead and change my i and j to maybe s and t, respectively.
所以让我将 i 和 j 分别改为 s 和 t。
So string s equals getstring.
所以 string s 等于 getstring。
And I'll ask for s, quote unquote.
我将获取 s，带引号。
And then string t equals getstring.
然后 string t 等于 getstring。
And then I'll ask for t, quote unquote.
然后我将获取 t，带引号。
And then down here, I'll compare s equals, equals t.
然后在下面，我将比较 s 等于 t。
So here's the code, almost the same logically.
这是代码，逻辑上几乎相同。
I'm just getting different data types instead, still using the CS50 library.
我只是获取不同的数据类型，仍然使用 CS50 库。
So let's do make compare again, dot slash compare.
让我们再次运行 make compare，然后运行 compare 程序。
And let's type in something like "HI" exclamation point,
让我们输入一些内容，例如 "HI" 感叹号，
"HI" exclamation point.
"HI" 感叹号。
And that's interesting.
这很有趣。
All right, let's maybe try it again.
好的，让我们再试一次。
So maybe lowercase "hi", "hi".
也许是小写 "hi"，"hi"。
No, those are different.
不，它们是不同的。
Let's do it one more time, like "hi", "bye".
让我们再试一次，例如 "hi"，"bye"。
OK, so it half works.
好的，它部分起作用了。
But it seems to be saying different no matter what.
但它似乎始终显示不同。
Well, why might that be?
为什么呢？
Well, let me first just peel back a layer.
让我先揭开一层。
We already know that strings don't technically exist.
我们已经知道，字符串并不真正存在。
They're really char star.
它们其实是 char star。
And string here is char star.
这里的 string 是 char star。
So does this reveal, perhaps implicitly, why
这是否揭示了，也许是隐含的，为什么
s and t are being thought to be different, even though I literally
s 和 t 被认为是不同的，即使我实际上
typed "hi" twice?
输入了两次 "hi"？
Yeah, on line nine here, I'm really just comparing
是的，在第 9 行，我实际上只是比较
the addresses that are in s and t, and that's why I changed it to char star,
s 和 t 中的地址，这就是我将其改为 char star 的原因，
just not to change anything, but to make it even clearer
并不是要改变任何东西，而是为了更清楚地表明
that s and t are, in fact, addresses.
s 和 t 实际上是地址。
They're not strings, per se.
它们本身不是字符串。
They're the address of the first character in those strings.
它们是这些字符串中第一个字符的地址。
And even though they happen to be the same words that I typed in,
即使它们碰巧是我输入的相同单词，
it would seem to imply that they're ending up in different places.
这似乎暗示着它们最终处于不同的位置。
So here's another canvas of memory for this program.
这是这个程序的另一个内存画布。
And here, for instance, might be s with enough room
例如，这里可能是 s，它有足够的存储空间，
for eight bytes up here as a pointer.
这里作为指针使用八个字节。
Here maybe is where "hi" ended up for this particular story.
也许，对于这个特定的故事，“hi” 就存储在这里。
Well, what's actually going in s?
那么，s 里面实际存储的是什么？
Well, if h is at OX123, i is at OX124, and so forth, what's going in
如果 h 在 OX123，i 在 OX124，等等，那么存储在
s is OX123.
s 中的值是 OX123。
But when I use get string a second time and type in "hi"
但是当我第二次使用 get string 函数输入 "hi"
exclamation point, even the exact same way, uppercase or lowercase,
感叹号时，即使采用完全相同的方式，大写或小写，
t is ending up, presumably, somewhere else in memory.
t 很可能存储在内存中的其他地方。
So it's maybe using these eight bytes over here.
所以它可能正在使用这里这八个字节。
The same letters, coincidentally, by nature of how getstring works,
巧合的是，由于 getstring 函数的工作原理，
are ending up in the computer's memory, maybe down there, bottom right
这些相同的字母最终存储在计算机内存中，可能在下面，右下角
hand corner.
的角落。
Those are presumably different addresses, OX456, 457, 458, 459.
这些地址很可能不同，OX456, 457, 458, 459。
So what's going to go in t as its value?
所以 t 的值将是什么？
OX456, according to this example.
根据这个例子，是 OX456。
And so when you literally compare s equals,
所以当你直接比较 s 等于
equals t, no, they're not the same.
等于 t 时，不，它们并不相同。
They are, in fact, different, even if what they're pointing at
事实上，它们是不同的，即使它们指向的是
happens to be the same.
相同的内容。
So the computer's taking us literally.
所以计算机是按照字面意思来理解的。
If you compare s and t respectively, it's
如果你分别比较 s 和 t，它
going to compare what their values actually are.
将比较它们的值是什么。
And their values are the addresses of the first letter
它们的值分别是第一个字母的地址
of this string, and the first letter of this string, respectively.
在这个字符串中的地址，和在这个字符串中的第一个字母的地址。
And if those addresses differ, which they clearly do,
如果这些地址不同，很明显它们是不同的，
they're going to be deemed different.
它们将被认为是不同的。
Now, you might wonder, well, this just seems stupidly inefficient.
现在，你可能想知道，好吧，这看起来太低效了。
Why put the same string in two different places?
为什么要把同一个字符串放在两个不同的地方？
Well, maybe the string needs to be changed later on,
好吧，也许这个字符串需要在以后进行修改，
and we might want to have two different versions thereof.
而且我们可能想要有这两个字符串的不同版本。
And frankly, the first time you call getstring, it does its thing.
坦率地说，第一次调用 getstring 函数时，它会执行它的操作。
The second time you call getstring, it does its own thing.
第二次调用 getstring 函数时，它会执行它自己的操作。
It doesn't necessarily know how many times it's been called in the past.
它不一定知道在过去被调用了多少次。
And so maybe there's no communication between those calls.
所以也许在这些调用之间没有通信。
And so surely, it's going to do the simple thing
因此，它肯定会做最简单的事情
and just create more memory, create more memory for each of those strings,
就是创建更多的内存，为每个字符串创建更多的内存，
duplicates though they may seem to be.
即使它们看起来像是重复的。
So what does this imply?
所以这意味着什么呢？
Well, you might recall that we avoided this problem altogether
你可能还记得，我们完全避免了这个问题
just a week ago by using what solution on line nine?
就在一周前，我们在第九行使用了什么解决方案？
I did not compare two strings using equals, equals last time.
上次我没有使用等于号来比较两个字符串。
Exactly.
没错。
We used the strcompare function, which is in string.h very deliberately
我们使用了 strcompare 函数，它在 string.h 中，这是特意选择的，
at the time, because I didn't want to trip over this mistake at the time
因为当时我不想在这个错误上绊倒，
until we were sort of ready and had the vocabulary to discuss it.
直到我们做好准备，并拥有讨论这个问题的词汇。
But I did not do s equals, equals t, even though, logically, that's
但是我没有做 s 等于 t，即使从逻辑上来说，这就是
what you're trying to do, compare for equality.
你想要做的事情，比较是否相等。
But if you know now what a string is, it's
但是如果你现在知道字符串是什么，它
an array of characters starting at some address.
是一个从某个地址开始的字符数组。
You really need someone something to do the heavy lifting
你真的需要有人或者某些东西来做重活
of comparing every one of those chars from left to right.
从左到右比较所有这些字符。
We did it ourselves last time by just implementing it in code two weeks ago.
我们上次通过在代码中实现它来自己做了这件事，那是两周前。
But strcompare compare does it for us.
但 strcompare 函数为我们做这件事。
So strcompare, s comma t actually weirdly returns three possible values,
所以 strcompare，s 逗号 t 实际上会返回三个可能的值，
zero if they're the same, a positive number if one comes before the other,
如果它们相同，则为零；如果一个在另一个之前，则为正数；
or a negative number if the opposite is true.
反之，则为负数。
So strcomp, remember, can be used for alphabetizing
所以 strcomp，请记住，可以用于字母排序
things, or ascii-betizing things, based on those Ascii values.
事物，或者基于 ASCII 值对事物进行 ASCII 排序。
So this version, if I open my terminal window now and do make compare,
所以这个版本，如果我现在打开我的终端窗口并执行 make compare，
dot slash compare, and type in "hi" and "hi", now, in fact,
点斜杠 compare，然后输入 "hi" 和 "hi"，现在，事实上，
they're the same because strcomp is doing the work
它们是相同的，因为 strcomp 正在做
of comparing them char by char.
逐个字符比较它们的工作。
And if I do "hi" and "bye", those are now, in fact, different.
如果我输入 "hi" 和 "bye"，它们现在事实上是不同的。
So we avoided the problem last time for this very reason that simply using
所以我们上次之所以避免了这个问题，正是因为简单地使用
equals, equals would not have worked.
等于号是行不通的。
Yes.
没错。
AUDIENCE: Using those values?
使用这些值？
Is it like one minus one, or one, two, three,
它像是一减一，还是一、二、三，
depending how different they are?
取决于它们有多不同？
SPEAKER 1: Oh, good question.
好的，这个问题问得好。
So when using strcompare, the documentation
所以在使用 strcompare 函数时，文档
says that it will return zero, or a positive number, or a negative number.
说明它会返回零，或正数，或负数。
It doesn't tell you a specific number.
它没有告诉你一个具体的数字。
So the magnitude of the integer that comes back actually has no meaning.
所以返回的整数的大小实际上没有任何意义。
It might very well be one, zero, and negative one, but there's no guarantee.
它很可能是 1、0 和 -1，但没有保证。
And so you can check for equality equals, equals,
所以你可以检查是否等于，等于，
or you should check for greater than or less
或者你应该检查是否大于或小于
than, but not specific to a certain number.
于，但不要具体到某个数字。
So it just gives you relative ordering.
所以它只提供相对顺序。
It doesn't give you any more detail than that.
它不会提供更多细节。
All right.
好的。
So if we were to now take this lesson a step further,
所以如果我们现在把这个教训再进一步，
just to hammer home this point, whereby these strings s and t must clearly
为了强调这一点，这些字符串 s 和 t 必须清楚地
live at different addresses, let's actually try to see this in code.
存储在不同的地址，让我们尝试在代码中查看这一点。
So let me go back to VS Code here.
所以让我回到这里的 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and just remove all of the conditional code,
让我继续，只删除所有条件代码，
and instead do something old school, like print out %s backslash n and print
而是做一些老式的事情，比如打印 %s 反斜杠 n 然后打印
out s.
s。
Then Let's go ahead and print out %s again, but print out t,
然后让我们继续打印 %s，但打印 t，
just to see the two strings as being duplicative.
只是为了看到这两个字符串是重复的。
So here I go.
所以我开始了。
Make compare dot slash compare, "hi" exclamation point,
Make compare 点斜杠 compare，"hi" 感叹号，
"hi" exclamation point.
“hi”感叹号。
And of course, they're actually the same.
当然，它们实际上是相同的。
But if I actually want to see where s and t are,
但如果我想真正地看到 s 和 t 在哪里，
I can change the % s to what?
我可以将 %s 更改为？
%p, %p here.
%p，%p 在这里。
And I don't need to use an ampersand before the s or the t
我不需要在 s 或 t 前面使用取地址符
because they are already addresses.
因为它们已经是地址了。
That was today's big reveal.
这就是今天的重大发现。
And it turns out that printf is smart enough when you use s,
事实证明，当你使用 s 时，printf 足够聪明，
and you give it an address of s, or the address in t, to just go there for you.
并且你给它一个 s 的地址，或者 t 中的地址，它会自动为你跳转到那里。
So printf has been doing all of that for us with %s.
所以 printf 一直在用 %s 为我们做这些。
But %p is actually going to print out those raw addresses.
但 %p 实际上会打印出这些原始地址。
So let me do make compare, dot slash compare, "hi" once, "hi" twice.
所以让我执行 make compare，然后 ./compare，“hi” 一次，“hi” 两次。
And here now, we should see the addresses at which "hi" lives.
现在这里，我们应该看到 “hi” 所处的地址。
And it's not going to be as simplistic as OX123 and OX456.
而且它不会像 OX123 和 OX456 那样简单。
But if I go back to my terminal and hit enter,
但如果我回到我的终端并按回车键，
indeed, I get two different hexadecimal values
确实，我得到了两个不同的十六进制值
that makes clear that, if I were to naively compare them with equals,
这清楚地表明，如果我天真地用等于号进行比较，
equals, they're always going to be different,
等于，它们总是会不同的，
even if I typed in the same words.
即使我输入了相同的词。
So there's implications now of this, especially if we want
所以现在这里有影响，特别是如果我们想要
to start changing things in memory.
开始更改内存中的东西。
So for instance, let me create a new program called copy.c.
例如，让我创建一个名为 copy.c 的新程序。
And in here, we'll start somewhat similarly with CS5o.h.
在这里，我们将使用 CS5o.h 开始类似的处理。
We'll start with standard io.h.
我们将从 stdio.h 开始。
And preemptively, I'm going to go ahead and include string.h, as well.
为了提前准备，我将继续包含 string.h。
I'm going to declare main as not taking any command line arguments.
我将声明 main 不接受任何命令行参数。
And this time, I'm just going to get one string s with getstring,
这次，我将使用 getstring 获取一个字符串 s，
and I'll prompt the user for s.
我将提示用户输入 s。
And now, let me go ahead and naively say this.
现在，让我天真地说一下。
Let me give myself a new string called t and just set it equal to s,
让我给自己一个新的名为 t 的字符串，并将其设置为等于 s，
my instinct being this is how I've copied integers before.
我的直觉是，这就是我之前复制整数的方式。
This is how I've copied floating point values before.
这就是我之前复制浮点数的方式。
This surely is how I copy strings, using the assignment operator as usual.
这肯定是我复制字符串的方式，像往常一样使用赋值运算符。
Let me now for the sake of discussion propose
现在为了讨论起见，我提议
that I want to capitalize the first letter in t,
我想将 t 中的第一个字母大写，
but not the first letter in s.
但不要将 s 中的第一个字母大写。
So logically, based on week two syntax, I'm going to go into the t string,
所以从逻辑上讲，基于第二周的语法，我将进入 t 字符串，
go to location zero, and set it equal to upper of t bracket zero.
转到位置零，并将其设置为 t 中括号内的第一个字母的大写。
So recall, we introduced two upper.
还记得我们介绍了两个 upper 函数吗？
It's just a handy function for capitalizing things.
它只是一个用于将字符大写的便捷函数。
There's two lower, and there's a bunch of others, as well.
还有两个 lower 函数，以及很多其他的函数。
I didn't include the header file yet, though, so I'm going to go back
不过，我还没有包含头文件，所以我要回去
and include--
包含--
anyone remember where these are?
有人记得这些函数在哪里吗？
Yeah, ctype.h.
是的，ctype.h。
And it's fine to look that up in the menu if you ever need it.
如果你需要，可以在菜单中查找。
So here, I am, a little naively, capitalizing the first letter in t.
所以这里，我有点天真地将 t 中的第一个字母大写。
Technically speaking, I should check what the length of t
从技术上讲，我应该检查 t 的长度
is first, because if there's no characters there, if it has zero chars,
首先，因为如果那里没有字符，如果它有零个字符，
there's nothing to uppercase.
就没有什么可以大写的。
But for now, I'm going to keep it simple and just blindly do that there.
但现在，我会保持简单，直接盲目地执行。
Now, let me go ahead and print out with %s the value of s.
现在，让我继续用 %s 打印出 s 的值。
Now, let me go ahead and print out with %s value of t.
现在，让我继续用 %s 打印出 t 的值。
And I should see one lowercase s and one capitalized T. All right, here we go.
我应该看到一个小写的 s 和一个大写的 T。好的，我们来试试看。
Make copy, dot slash copy.
执行 make copy，然后 ./copy。
And I'm going to deliberately type it in lowercase.
我将故意用小写字母输入。
"hi" exclamation point, and we should see now they're both capitalized,
“hi”感叹号，现在我们应该看到它们都变成了大写，
it would seem.
看起来是这样。
Intuitively, why might that be?
直觉上，为什么会出现这种情况呢？
Exactly, the addresses are the same.
没错，地址是一样的。
So if I do use the assignment operator and just do t equals s semicolon,
所以如果我使用赋值运算符，并且只是执行 t 等于 s 分号，
it's going to take me literally and copy the address in s over to t,
它将从字面上将 s 中的地址复制到 t 中，
so that effectively, they're pointing at the same thing.
因此，实际上，它们指向同一个东西。
So if we draw another picture here, for instance, here maybe is s,
所以如果我们在这里再画一张图，例如，这里可能是 s，
and here maybe is the lowercase "hi" that I first type
这里可能是第一次输入的小写 “hi”
in down here in memory.
在内存中的下方。
Maybe that's at OX123 again, and therefore that's what's in s.
也许它再次在 OX123 上，因此这就是 s 中的内容。
When I then create the variable t by declaring it to be a string,
当我随后声明变量 t 为一个字符串时，
as well, that gives me another variable here called t.
它也给了我一个名为 t 的变量。
But I'm just setting it equal to s.
但我只是将它设置为等于 s。
I'm not calling getstring again in this version of copy.
在这个版本的 copy 中，我没有再次调用 getstring。
That was in compare.
那是在 compare 中。
In copy, I'm just literally copying s into t.
在 copy 中，我仅仅是字面上将 s 复制到 t 中。
So that literally just changes the value to OX123, also.
所以它从字面上将值更改为 OX123。
And if we abstract away all of these addresses,
如果我们抽象掉所有这些地址，
that's essentially like s and t both pointing to the same place.
本质上就像 s 和 t 都指向同一个位置。
So if I use s bracket zero, or t bracket zero, they are one and the same.
所以如果我使用 s 括号中的第一个字母，或者 t 括号中的第一个字母，它们是一样的。
So when I use t bracket zero to use uppercase,
所以当我使用 t 括号内的第一个字母来使用 uppercase 时，
it's changing that lowercase h to capital H.
它将小写 h 更改为大写 H。
But again, both strings, both pointers are pointing at the same value.
但再次强调，这两个字符串，两个指针都指向同一个值。
And again, this should be even clearer as of today.
而且，从今天开始，这一点应该更加清楚。
If I go back into VS Code and, indeed, take these training wheels off,
如果我回到 VS Code 中，并且确实去掉了这些辅助轮，
and treat string as what it is, char star, which indicates that both s and t
并将字符串视为它本来的样子，char *，这表明 s 和 t 都是
are just addresses, which makes even clearer, syntactically,
地址，从语法上讲，这更加清楚地表明，
that this is probably the picture that's going on underneath the hood.
这可能是在幕后发生的事情。
Now, just to make the code a little more robust,
现在，为了使代码更加健壮，
let me at least be a little careful here.
至少让我在这里小心一点。
If the string length of t is greater than zero, then and only then,
如果 t 的字符串长度大于零，那么也只有在此时，
should I really blindly index into the string and go to location zero.
我才应该盲目地索引到字符串中，并转到位置零。
That doesn't really solve the fundamental problem,
这并不能真正解决根本问题，
but it at least avoids a situation where maybe the user just hits enter,
但至少它避免了一种情况，即用户可能只是按下了回车键，
gives me no characters, and I try to blindly
没有给我任何字符，我尝试盲目地
uppercase something that's not there.
将不存在的东西大写。
But there's still a bug.
但仍然存在一个错误。
There's still a bug.
仍然存在一个错误。
So how do I actually solve this?
那么我该如何解决这个问题呢？
Well, it turns out we need two other functions
事实证明，我们需要另外两个函数
that we haven't had occasion to use.
我们还没有机会使用。
But these are perhaps the most powerful, and they're
但它们可能是最强大的，而且它们
going to allow us to solve even grander problems next week when
将在下周我们讨论更大型事物，即数据结构时，让我们解决更大的问题。
we discuss all the more, things called data structures.
我们讨论更大型事物，即数据结构时，让我们解决更大的问题。
But for now, let's very simply solve this idea of copying a string.
但现在，让我们非常简单地解决这个复制字符串的想法。
Let me go back into VS Code here, and let me give myself one more header file
让我回到 VS Code 中，再给自己添加一个头文件
that's called standard lib for standard library.
名为 standard lib，用于标准库。
So include standard lib dot h, in which both of these functions,
所以包含 standard lib.h，这两个函数都在里面，
malloc and free, are declared for me.
malloc 和 free，都已为我声明。
And now, in my code, I'm going to behave a little bit differently here.
现在，在我的代码中，我将在这里稍作更改。
Clearly, I got into trouble by just blindly copying the addresses.
显然，我只是盲目地复制地址，因此遇到了麻烦。
What I really want to do when I copy strings, presumably, and then
我想做的，假设，是在我复制字符串，然后
uppercase one of them, is I want to create
将其中一个大写，我想创建一个
a duplicate string, a second array that is identical,
一个重复的字符串，一个与之相同的第二个数组，
but is elsewhere in memory.
但它在内存中的其他位置。
So the way to do this might be as follows.
所以，可以这样做。
Instead of just setting t equal to s, I should really
我应该真正调用这个名为 malloc 的新函数，而不是仅仅将 t 设置为 s，
call this brand new function called malloc,
我应该真正调用这个名为 malloc 的新函数，
which stands for memory allocate, and it takes a single argument,
它代表内存分配，并且它接受一个参数，
which is just the number of bytes you would like the operating system
它只是你想让操作系统分配给你的字节数。
to allocate for you.
分配给你的字节数。
So whether you're using this on Windows, Mac OS, or Linux in our case,
所以无论你在我们的情况下是在 Windows、Mac OS 还是 Linux 上使用它，
this is a way I can literally ask the operating system,
这是一种我可以直接向操作系统询问的方法，
please find for me some number of bytes in the computer's memory
请在计算机内存中为我找到一些字节
that I can now use for my own purposes.
我现在可以用来做自己的事情。
So malloc here, I technically need at least three bytes,
所以这里的 malloc，我技术上至少需要 3 个字节，
but that's not going to be enough because I
但这还不够，因为我
need a fourth for the null character.
需要第四个字节来存储空字符。
So I could put four here.
所以我可以在这里放四个字节。
But that's stupid.
但那很愚蠢。
I shouldn't just hardcode a number like this we've seen.
我们已经看到，我不应该像这样硬编码一个数字。
So I could probably do strlen of s to dynamically figure out
所以我可以动态地使用 strlen(s) 来计算出
how many bytes I want for the copy.
我想要复制多少字节。
But that, too, is not enough because string length
但这也不够，因为字符串长度
returns the human readable length, so H-I exclamation point.
返回的是人类可读的长度，所以是 H-I 感叹号。
So I think I want a plus one in there, too.
所以我想在那里加一个一。
So that just means get the length of whatever the human typed in,
所以这意味着获取人类输入的长度，
add one for the null character to make sure that we're not undercounting.
加一，以确保我们没有少算。
Now, what can I then do?
现在，我该怎么办呢？
Unfortunately, I need to do a bit of work here.
不幸的是，我需要在这里做一些工作。
So let me actually go ahead now and do something like this.
所以现在让我实际去做一些类似的事情。
For int i equals zero, I is less than the string length of s, i plus, plus.
对于 int i 等于 0，i 小于 s 的字符串长度，i 加加。
And then inside of this loop, I could copy into the ith location of t,
然后在这个循环里面，我可以将 s 的第 i 个位置复制到 t 的第 i 个位置。
whatever is in the ith location of s.
复制 s 的第 i 个位置的内容。
Now, this is a little buggy.
现在，这有点小错误。
One, this is inefficient to keep asking this question.
第一，这在设计上是不高效的，因为不断地问这个问题。
We talked about this in the context of design.
我们在设计背景下讨论过这个问题。
I should probably improve this by giving myself a variable like n,
我应该通过给自己一个像 n 这样的变量来改进它，
set that equal to the string length, and then do i is less than n
将其设置为字符串长度，然后执行 i 小于 n
again, and again, just so I'm not stupidly
一遍又一遍，这样我就不会愚蠢地
calling string length four different times, or three different times.
四次或三次调用字符串长度。
But this, too, is slightly buggy, and this one's very subtle.
但这也有点小错误，而且这个错误很微妙。
This does not fully copy s into t.
这并没有完全将 s 复制到 t 中。
Does anyone see the very subtle bug that I've introduced?
有人注意到我引入的这个非常微妙的错误吗？
Sorry?
抱歉？
Yeah, I'm forgetting the backslash zero.
是的，我忘记了反斜杠零。
So even though I'm copying H-I exclamation point,
所以即使我复制了 H-I 感叹号，
or whatever the human typed in, I need to go one step further deliberately
或者人类输入的任何内容，我需要有意地再走一步
to make sure I also copy the backslash zero,
以确保我也复制了反斜杠零，
or at least manually put it in myself.
或者至少手动添加它。
So I could solve this by, either doing this up to and through n,
所以我可以通过以下方法解决这个问题：要么这样做，直到 n，
i is less than or equal to n, or I could plus one here.
i 小于或等于 n，或者我可以在此处加 1。
That, too, would be fine.
这样也可以。
Or if I really want, I could do this, like t bracket
或者，如果我真的想，我可以这样做，比如 t 括号
three equals, quote unquote, backslash zero.
三个等于号，引号，反斜杠零。
But again, I shouldn't get into the habit of hard coding things.
但同样地，我不应该养成硬编码的习惯。
I could do string length of s, and that would give me the last location in s,
我可以执行 strlen(s)，这会给我 s 的最后一个位置，
which would also work.
这样也可以。
But that, too, is stupid.
但这也很愚蠢。
I might as well--
我也可以
or just unnecessarily complex.
或者只是不必要的复杂。
Let's just do this, change one symbol, and boom.
让我们这样做，改变一个符号，然后砰的一声。
Now we're copying all three, and the fourth character, as well.
现在我们正在复制所有三个字符，以及第四个字符。
All right, so with this said, let's go ahead now
好的，说了这么多，现在让我们
and make sure that t is indeed of length at least greater than zero.
确保 t 的长度至少大于 0。
Then let's go ahead and capitalize t as before and print out the results.
然后让我们像之前一样将 t 大写并打印出结果。
So let me go ahead and open my terminal window, make copy, dot slash copy,
所以，让我打开我的终端窗口，复制，点斜杠 copy，
and I'm going to deliberately type "hi" in lowercase.
我要故意用小写输入 "hi"。
And now we should see disparate s and t.
现在我们应该看到 s 和 t 不同。
s is now still lowercase, and T is now capitalized.
s 现在仍然是小写，而 T 现在是大写的。
But why is that exactly?
但为什么正是这样呢？
Well, let me actually go into, say, my computer's memory
好吧，让我实际进入，比如，我的计算机内存
again and propose that, if what I had before
再次，并提出，如果我之前拥有的
was this situation, where s is pointing at this chunk of memory,
是这种情况，s 指向这块内存，
and t was accidentally pointing in that same chunk of memory, what we really
而 t 意外地指向了同一块内存，我们真正
want to do is have t point at a new chunk of memory.
想要做的就是让 t 指向一块新的内存。
And malloc is what gives us this chunk of memory.
而 malloc 就是让我们获得这块内存的工具。
And then using that for loop, can I copy the H, the I, the exclamation point,
然后使用那个 for 循环，我可以复制 H、I、感叹号，
and even the backslash zero.
甚至包括反斜杠零。
So now, this is a little subtle, but malloc is what gives me
现在，这有点微妙，但 malloc 就是给我
access to this new chunk of memory.
访问这块新内存的方法。
Malloc takes one argument, the number of bytes that you want it to find for you.
Malloc 接受一个参数，即你想要它为你找到的字节数。
Take a guess.
猜猜看。
What value is malloc returning?
Malloc 返回的是什么值？
Conceptually, it's returning a chunk of memory, but that's kind of handwavy.
从概念上讲，它返回的是一块内存，但这有点含糊。
What might malloc actually be returning?
Malloc 实际上返回的可能是？
AUDIENCE: Maybe the pointer to the first character?
听众：可能是指向第一个字符的指针？
SPEAKER 1: Perfect.
演讲者 1：完美！
malloc is returning the address of that chunk of memory, not the last address.
Malloc 返回的是那块内存的地址，而不是最后一个地址。
The first address.
第一个地址。
And here's a difference with strings.
这里与字符串有所不同。
This chunk of memory is not magically terminated with null for you.
这块内存不会自动以空字符结尾。
I had to do that with for loop. malloc, and in turn, your operating system,
我必须使用 for 循环来完成。Malloc，以及你的操作系统，
does keep track of how big these chunks of memory are.
会跟踪这些内存块的大小。
So even though it's only returning the address
所以，即使它只返回
of the first byte of that memory, the operating system
第一个字节的地址，操作系统
is going to know that it used up four bytes here, four bytes here.
会知道这里用了四个字节，这里用了四个字节。
And it will keep track of that so that it
它会跟踪这些信息，以便它
doesn't give you an overlapping address in the future
不会在将来给你一个重叠的地址
because that would be bad.
因为那样会很糟糕。
Your data would get corrupted.
你的数据会损坏。
But you, similarly, have to remember or figure out how many bytes are available
但你同样需要记住或弄清楚还有多少字节可用
thereafter.
之后。
It's up to you to manage it, as by putting a null character there
你需要自己管理它，例如通过在里面放入一个空字符
yourself.
自己完成。
So if I go back to my code now, let me actually
所以，如果我现在回到我的代码，让我实际
harden this code just a little bit more as follows,
稍微加强一下这段代码，如下所示，
whereby I can do this a little better.
这样我就能更好地做到这一点。
If I go back to VS Code here, it turns out, if something goes wrong
如果我回到这里 VS Code，结果发现，如果出现错误
and I'm out of memory, maybe I've got an old computer,
而且我的内存不足，也许我的电脑太旧了，
or maybe I'm typing something way bigger than three characters in,
或者我输入了超过三个字符的文本，
like three billion characters, and the computer
比如三十亿个字符，而电脑
might genuinely run out of memory.
可能真的会内存不足。
I actually should be in the habit of doing this.
我实际上应该养成这样的习惯。
If t equals, equals a special symbol called null with two Ls,
如果 t 等于等于一个名为 null 的特殊符号，有两个 L，
and I promised this would eventually exist,
我承诺过这个符号最终会存在，
I should just return one now, or return two, return negative one,
我应该现在就返回 1，或者返回 2，返回负 1，
return any value other than zero, and just abort the program early.
返回任何非零值，并提前终止程序。
That means, if malloc returns null, there's not enough memory available.
这意味着，如果 malloc 返回空，则意味着可用内存不足。
And it turns out, all this time, I'm going to do one other crazy thing,
结果发现，一直以来，我还要做一件疯狂的事，
even though we've not expected you to do this thus far.
尽管我们之前没有期望你这样做。
Technically, when using getstring, getstring,
从技术上讲，当使用 getstring 时，getstring，
if you read the documentation, the manual, it too can return null.
如果你阅读文档，手册，它也可以返回空。
Because if you type in a crazy long string,
因为如果你输入一个很长的字符串，
and the computer can't fit it in its memory,
而电脑无法将其存储在内存中，
getstring needs to signal that to you somehow.
getstring 需要以某种方式向你发出信号。
And the documentation actually says that, if getstring returns null,
文档实际上说，如果 getstring 返回空，
then you too should not trust what's in it.
那你也不应该相信里面的内容。
You should just exit the program immediately, in this case.
在这种情况下，你应该立即退出程序。
But there's one other improvement we can make here.
但我们这里还可以进行另一个改进。
And even though this is making the code seem way longer than it is,
尽管这使得代码看起来比实际长很多，
most of this I've just added is just error checking,
但我添加的大部分内容都是错误检查，
just mindless error checking to make sure that I don't treat s as being
只是机械地检查错误，确保我不将 s 视为
valid, or t as being valid when it isn't.
有效的，或者将 t 视为有效的，而实际上它不是。
It turns out this is stupid.
结果发现，这很愚蠢。
I don't need to reinvent this wheel.
我不需要重新发明轮子。
Certainly, for decades, people have been copying strings, even in C.
当然，几十年来，人们一直在复制字符串，即使是在 C 语言中。
So it turns out there's another fun function called strcopy, wonderfully
结果发现，还有一个有趣的函数叫做 strcopy，非常棒
enough, that takes the destination as its first argument,
而且它将目标作为第一个参数，
the source as its second argument.
源作为第二个参数。
And that will for me copy s into t, respectively.
它会帮我将 s 复制到 t 中，分别。
So that does the equivalent of that for loop, including the backslash zero.
所以它等效于那个 for 循环，包括反斜杠零。
However, there's one other function recall that was on our cheat sheet
但是，还记得我们之前的备忘单上有一个函数
a moment ago, whereby malloc is accompanied
吗？它就是 malloc，它伴随着
by one other function called Free.
另一个函数，叫做 Free。
So Free is the opposite of malloc.
所以 Free 是 malloc 的反向操作。
When you're done with your computer's memory,
当你不再需要电脑的内存时，
you're supposed to give it back to Windows, to Mac OS, to Linux
你应该把它还给 Windows、Mac OS 或者 Linux，
so it can reuse it for something else.
以便它可以将其用于其他用途。
And frankly, if you've ever been using your computer for hours
坦白地说，如果你曾经连续使用电脑数小时
on end, days on end, and maybe it's getting slower, and slower,
甚至连续使用数天，可能电脑会变得越来越慢，
maybe it's Photoshop, maybe it's a really big document, generally,
可能是 Photoshop，也可能是一个很大的文档，一般来说，
really big files consume lots and lots of memory.
很大的文件会占用很多内存。
If the humans who wrote that software, be it Photoshop or something else,
如果编写该软件的人，无论是 Photoshop 还是其他软件，
wrote buggy code and kept using malloc, malloc, malloc, malloc, asking
写了有错误的代码，并不断使用 malloc，malloc，malloc，malloc，请求
for more and more memory, but they never call the opposite function, Free,
越来越多的内存，但他们从未调用反向函数 Free，
your computer might actually run out of memory.
你的电脑可能会真的内存不足。
And typically, the symptom is that it gets so darn
而典型的症状是电脑会变得非常慢，
slow it becomes annoying to use.
慢到让人厌烦。
And frankly, the mouse starts moving very slowly, maybe the thing freezes
坦白地说，鼠标开始移动得很慢，可能电脑会完全卡住
altogether, the computer crashes.
甚至崩溃。
Bad things happen when you run out of memory.
内存不足时，会发生不好的事情。
So in my case here, if I go back to VS Code,
所以，在我的例子中，如果我回到 VS Code，
it's actually on me in this language called C to actually manage
实际上，在这门叫做 C 的语言中，我需要自己管理
the memory myself so that, when I have called malloc,
内存，以便在我调用 malloc 之后，
thereafter, I had better free that same memory.
我最好释放相同的内存。
Now, I don't want to free it right away.
当然，我不想马上释放它。